<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<RECIPES>
  <RECIPE>
    <AGE>14</AGE>
    <FERMENTATION_STAGES>1</FERMENTATION_STAGES>
    <BATCH_SIZE>3.7854117891320316</BATCH_SIZE>
    <SECONDARY_TEMP>21.0</SECONDARY_TEMP>
    <TYPE>Partial Mash</TYPE>
    <BOIL_SIZE>4.731764736415039</BOIL_SIZE>
    <TERTIARY_TEMP>21.0</TERTIARY_TEMP>
    <DISPLAY_OG>0.0</DISPLAY_OG>
    <NAME>Belgian Pumpkin Ale</NAME>
    <FG>1.011</FG>
    <EQUIPMENT/>
    <SECONDARY_AGE>0</SECONDARY_AGE>
    <PRIMARY_AGE>14</PRIMARY_AGE>
    <OG>1.048</OG>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <PRIMARY_TEMP>21.0</PRIMARY_TEMP>
    <NOTES>Pumpkin will add additional ABV</NOTES>
    <DISPLAY_FG>0.0</DISPLAY_FG>
    <BREWER/>
    <TERTIARY_AGE>0</TERTIARY_AGE>
    <BOIL_TIME>60</BOIL_TIME>
    <EFFICIENCY>60.0</EFFICIENCY>
    <HOPS>
      <HOP>
        <NAME>Nugget</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <ALPHA>14.1</ALPHA>
        <AMOUNT>8.5049E-4</AMOUNT>
        <USE>Boil</USE>
        <TIME>60</TIME>
        <NOTES>No description</NOTES>
        <TYPE>Hop</TYPE>
        <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
      </HOP>
      <HOP>
        <NAME>Hallertau</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <ALPHA>2.5</ALPHA>
        <AMOUNT>0.00708738</AMOUNT>
        <USE>Boil</USE>
        <TIME>30</TIME>
        <NOTES>No description</NOTES>
        <TYPE>Hop</TYPE>
        <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
      </HOP>
      <HOP>
        <NAME>Hallertau</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <ALPHA>2.5</ALPHA>
        <AMOUNT>0.00708738</AMOUNT>
        <USE>Boil</USE>
        <TIME>15</TIME>
        <NOTES>No description</NOTES>
        <TYPE>Hop</TYPE>
        <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
      </HOP>
    </HOPS>
    <FERMENTABLES>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Pilsen Light DME</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Extract</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.34019428</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>90.87999999999992</YIELD>
        <COLOR>1.899999976158142</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Munich (German)</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Grain</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.13607771</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>80.06000000000016</YIELD>
        <COLOR>8.0</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Two-row (US)</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Grain</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.09071847</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>80.06000000000016</YIELD>
        <COLOR>1.7999999523162842</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Biscuit (Belgian)</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Grain</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.06803886</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>75.72999999999993</YIELD>
        <COLOR>24.0</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Crystal 40L</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Grain</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.04535924</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>73.5700000000001</YIELD>
        <COLOR>40.0</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
    </FERMENTABLES>
    <MISCS>
      <MISC>
        <AMOUNT_IS_WEIGHT>false</AMOUNT_IS_WEIGHT>
        <AMOUNT>0.22686025</AMOUNT>
        <USE_FOR>Boil</USE_FOR>
        <TYPE>Misc</TYPE>
        <VERSION>1</VERSION>
        <NOTES>Custom misc</NOTES>
        <NAME>Pumpkin Extract</NAME>
        <USE>Boil</USE>
        <DISPLAY_AMOUNT>0.5 lbs</DISPLAY_AMOUNT>
        <DISPLAY_TIME>30 mins</DISPLAY_TIME>
      </MISC>
      <MISC>
        <AMOUNT_IS_WEIGHT>false</AMOUNT_IS_WEIGHT>
        <AMOUNT>0.00246446</AMOUNT>
        <USE_FOR>Boil</USE_FOR>
        <TYPE>Misc</TYPE>
        <VERSION>1</VERSION>
        <NOTES>Custom misc</NOTES>
        <NAME>Pumpkin Pie Spice</NAME>
        <USE>Boil</USE>
        <DISPLAY_AMOUNT>0.49999999999999994 tsp</DISPLAY_AMOUNT>
        <DISPLAY_TIME>5 mins</DISPLAY_TIME>
      </MISC>
    </MISCS>
    <YEASTS>
      <YEAST>
        <NAME>Safbrew T-58</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Yeast</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.0</AMOUNT>
        <LABORATORY>Fermentis</LABORATORY>
        <PRODUCT_ID>T-58</PRODUCT_ID>
        <MIN_TEMPERATURE>0</MIN_TEMPERATURE>
        <MAX_TEMPERATURE>0</MAX_TEMPERATURE>
        <ATTENUATION>75.0</ATTENUATION>
      </YEAST>
    </YEASTS>
    <WATERS/>
    <MASH>
      <TUN_WEIGHT>160.00000000</TUN_WEIGHT>
      <GRAIN_TEMP>22.22222220</GRAIN_TEMP>
      <VERSION>1</VERSION>
      <NAME>BIAB, Medium Body</NAME>
      <NOTES>Brew in a bag method where the full boil volume is mashed within the boil vessel and then the grains are withdrawn at the end of the mash.  No active sparging is required.  This is a medium body beer profile.</NOTES>
      <TUN_SPECIFIC_HEAT>0.30000000</TUN_SPECIFIC_HEAT>
      <EQUIP_ADJUST>FALSE</EQUIP_ADJUST>
      <TUN_TEMP>22.22222220</TUN_TEMP>
      <SPARGE_TEMP>75.60000000</SPARGE_TEMP>
      <PH>5.20000000</PH>
      <MASH_STEPS>
        <MASH_STEP>
          <RAMP_TIME>10.00000000</RAMP_TIME>
          <STEP_TEMP>66.70000000</STEP_TEMP>
          <INFUSE_AMOUNT>5.07195902</INFUSE_AMOUNT>
          <END_TIME>66.70000000</END_TIME>
          <STEP_TIME>75.00000000</STEP_TIME>
          <TYPE>Infusion</TYPE>
          <VERSION>1</VERSION>
          <NAME>Saccharification</NAME>
        </MASH_STEP>
        <MASH_STEP>
          <RAMP_TIME>7.00000000</RAMP_TIME>
          <STEP_TEMP>75.55555560</STEP_TEMP>
          <INFUSE_AMOUNT>0.00000000</INFUSE_AMOUNT>
          <END_TIME>75.55555560</END_TIME>
          <STEP_TIME>10.00000000</STEP_TIME>
          <TYPE>Temperature</TYPE>
          <VERSION>1</VERSION>
          <NAME>Mash Out</NAME>
        </MASH_STEP>
      </MASH_STEPS>
    </MASH>
    <STYLE>
      <PROFILE>Aroma: Variable. Most exhibit varying amounts of fruity esters, spicy phenols and/or yeast-borne aromatics. Aromas from actual spice additions may be present. Hop aroma may be none to high, and may include a dry-hopped character. Malt aroma may be low to high, and may include character of non-barley grains such as wheat or rye. Some may include aromas of Belgian microbiota, most commonly Brettanomyces and/or Lactobacillus. No diacetyl. Appearance: Variable. Color varies considerably from pale gold to very dark. Clarity may be hazy to clear. Head retention is usually good. Generally moderate to high carbonation. Flavor: Variable. A great variety of flavors are found in these beers. Maltiness may be light to quite rich. Hop flavor and bitterness may be low to high. Spicy flavors may be imparted by yeast (phenolics) and/or actual spice additions. May include characteristics of grains other than barley, such as wheat or rye. May include flavors produced by Belgian microbiota such as Brettanomyces or Lactobacillus. May include flavors from adjuncts such as caramelized sugar syrup or honey. Mouthfeel: Variable. Some are well-attenuated, thus fairly light-bodied for their original gravity, while others are thick and rich. Most are moderately to highly carbonated. A warming sensation from alcohol may be present in stronger examples. A “mouth puckering” sensation may be present from acidity.</PROFILE>
      <ABV_MIN>3.00000000</ABV_MIN>
      <CARB_MAX>0.00000000</CARB_MAX>
      <FG_MAX>1.01900000</FG_MAX>
      <IBU_MAX>40.00000000</IBU_MAX>
      <TYPE>Ale</TYPE>
      <NAME>Belgian Specialty Ale</NAME>
      <STYLE_GUIDE>BJCP 2008</STYLE_GUIDE>
      <OG_MIN>1.03000000</OG_MIN>
      <CATEGORY>Belgian and French Ale</CATEGORY>
      <OG_MAX>1.08000000</OG_MAX>
      <COLOR_MIN>3.00000000</COLOR_MIN>
      <ABV_MAX>9.00000000</ABV_MAX>
      <EXAMPLES>Orval; De Dolle’s Arabier, Oerbier, Boskeun and Stille Nacht; La Chouffe, McChouffe, Chouffe Bok and N’ice Chouffe; Ellezelloise Hercule Stout and Quintine Amber; Unibroue Ephemere, Maudite, Don de Dieu, etc.; Minty; Zatte Bie; Caracole Amber, Saxo and Nostradamus; Silenrieu Sara and Joseph; Fantome Black Ghost and Speciale Noel; Dupont Moinette, Moinette Brune, and Avec Les Bons Voeux de la Brasserie Dupont; St. Fullien Noel; Gouden Carolus Noel; Affligem Noel; Guldenburg and Pere Noel; De Ranke XX Bitter and Guldenberg; Poperings Hommelbier; Bush (Scaldis); Moinette Brune; Grottenbier; La Trappe Quadrupel; Weyerbacher QUAD; Biere de Miel; Verboden Vrucht; New Belgium 1554 Black Ale; Cantillon Iris; Russian River Temptation; Lost Abbey Cuvee de Tomme and Devotion, Lindemans Kriek and Framboise, and many more</EXAMPLES>
      <INGREDIENTS>May include herbs and/or spices. May include unusual grains and malts, though the grain character should be apparent if it is a key ingredient. May include adjuncts such as caramelized sugar syrup and honey. May include Belgian microbiota such as Brettanomyces or Lactobacillus. Unusual techniques, such as blending, may be used through primarily to arrive at a particular result. The process alone does not make a beer unique to a blind judging panel if the final product does not taste different.</INGREDIENTS>
      <FG_MIN>1.00600000</FG_MIN>
      <STYLE_LETTER>E</STYLE_LETTER>
      <VERSION>1</VERSION>
      <NOTES>Variable. This category encompasses a wide range of Belgian ales produced by truly artisanal brewers more concerned with creating unique products than in increasing sales. Unique beers of small, independent Belgian breweries that have come to enjoy local popularity but may be far less well-known outside of their own regions. Many have attained “cult status” in the U.S. (and other parts of the world) and now owe a significant portion of their sales to export. This is a catch-all category for any Belgian-style beer not fitting any other Belgian style category. The category can be used for clones of specific beers (e.g., Orval, La Chouffe); to produce a beer fitting a broader style that doesn’t have its own category; or to create an artisanal or experimental beer of the brewer’s own choosing (e.g., strong Belgian golden ale with spices, something unique). Creativity is the only limit in brewing but the entrants must identify what is special about their entry. This category may be used as an “incubator” for recognized styles for which there is not yet a formal BJCP category. Some styles falling into this classification include: • Blond Trappist table beer • Artisanal Blond • Artisanal Amber • Artisanal Brown • Belgian-style Barleywines • Trappist Quadrupels • Belgian Spiced Christmas Beers • Belgian Stout • Belgian IPA • Strong and/or Dark Saison • Fruit-based Flanders Red/Brown The judges must understand the brewer’s intent in order to properly judge an entry in this category. THE BREWER MUST SPECIFY EITHER THE BEER BEING CLONED, THE NEW STYLE BEING PRODUCED OR THE SPECIAL INGREDIENTS OR PROCESSES USED. Additional background information on the style and/or beer may be provided to judges to assist in the judging, including style parameters or detailed descriptions of the beer. Beers fitting other Belgian categories should not be entered in this category.</NOTES>
      <IBU_MIN>15.00000000</IBU_MIN>
      <CARB_MIN>0.00000000</CARB_MIN>
      <COLOR_MAX>50.00000000</COLOR_MAX>
      <CATEGORY_NUMBER>16</CATEGORY_NUMBER>
    </STYLE>
  </RECIPE>
  <RECIPE>
    <AGE>14</AGE>
    <FERMENTATION_STAGES>1</FERMENTATION_STAGES>
    <BATCH_SIZE>4.731764736415039</BATCH_SIZE>
    <SECONDARY_TEMP>21.0</SECONDARY_TEMP>
    <TYPE>Partial Mash</TYPE>
    <BOIL_SIZE>6.624470630981055</BOIL_SIZE>
    <TERTIARY_TEMP>21.0</TERTIARY_TEMP>
    <DISPLAY_OG>0.0</DISPLAY_OG>
    <NAME>Belgian Witbier</NAME>
    <FG>1.009</FG>
    <EQUIPMENT/>
    <SECONDARY_AGE>0</SECONDARY_AGE>
    <PRIMARY_AGE>14</PRIMARY_AGE>
    <OG>1.04</OG>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <PRIMARY_TEMP>21.0</PRIMARY_TEMP>
    <NOTES/>
    <DISPLAY_FG>0.0</DISPLAY_FG>
    <BREWER/>
    <TERTIARY_AGE>0</TERTIARY_AGE>
    <BOIL_TIME>60</BOIL_TIME>
    <EFFICIENCY>75.0</EFFICIENCY>
    <HOPS>
      <HOP>
        <NAME>Centennial</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <ALPHA>7.8</ALPHA>
        <AMOUNT>0.00283495</AMOUNT>
        <USE>Boil</USE>
        <TIME>60</TIME>
        <NOTES>No description</NOTES>
        <TYPE>Hop</TYPE>
        <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
      </HOP>
    </HOPS>
    <FERMENTABLES>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Wheat DME</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Extract</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.31751466</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>80.06000000000016</YIELD>
        <COLOR>3.0</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Wheat (Belgian)</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Grain</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.18143695</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>82.23000000000005</YIELD>
        <COLOR>1.7999999523162842</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Barley, Flaked</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Grain</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.06803886</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>69.23999999999988</YIELD>
        <COLOR>1.7000000476837158</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Flaked Oats</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Adjunct</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.06803886</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>71.40999999999977</YIELD>
        <COLOR>2.200000047683716</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Two-row (US)</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Grain</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.06803886</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>80.06000000000016</YIELD>
        <COLOR>1.7999999523162842</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
    </FERMENTABLES>
    <MISCS/>
    <YEASTS>
      <YEAST>
        <NAME>Belgian Witbier</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Yeast</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.12</AMOUNT>
        <LABORATORY>Wyeast Labs</LABORATORY>
        <PRODUCT_ID>3944</PRODUCT_ID>
        <MIN_TEMPERATURE>20</MIN_TEMPERATURE>
        <MAX_TEMPERATURE>20</MAX_TEMPERATURE>
        <ATTENUATION>74.0</ATTENUATION>
      </YEAST>
    </YEASTS>
    <WATERS/>
    <MASH>
      <TUN_WEIGHT>160.00000000</TUN_WEIGHT>
      <GRAIN_TEMP>22.22222220</GRAIN_TEMP>
      <VERSION>1</VERSION>
      <NAME>BIAB, Full Body</NAME>
      <NOTES>Brew in a bag method where the full boil volume is mashed within the boil vessel and then the grains are withdrawn at the end of the mash.  No active sparging is required. This is a full body beer profile.</NOTES>
      <TUN_SPECIFIC_HEAT>0.30000000</TUN_SPECIFIC_HEAT>
      <EQUIP_ADJUST>FALSE</EQUIP_ADJUST>
      <TUN_TEMP>22.22222220</TUN_TEMP>
      <SPARGE_TEMP>75.60000000</SPARGE_TEMP>
      <PH>5.20000000</PH>
      <MASH_STEPS>
        <MASH_STEP>
          <RAMP_TIME>10.00000000</RAMP_TIME>
          <STEP_TEMP>68.90000000</STEP_TEMP>
          <INFUSE_AMOUNT>7.01002416</INFUSE_AMOUNT>
          <END_TIME>68.90000000</END_TIME>
          <STEP_TIME>60.00000000</STEP_TIME>
          <TYPE>Infusion</TYPE>
          <VERSION>1</VERSION>
          <NAME>Saccharification</NAME>
        </MASH_STEP>
        <MASH_STEP>
          <RAMP_TIME>7.00000000</RAMP_TIME>
          <STEP_TEMP>75.55555560</STEP_TEMP>
          <INFUSE_AMOUNT>0.00000000</INFUSE_AMOUNT>
          <END_TIME>75.55555560</END_TIME>
          <STEP_TIME>10.00000000</STEP_TIME>
          <TYPE>Temperature</TYPE>
          <VERSION>1</VERSION>
          <NAME>Mash Out</NAME>
        </MASH_STEP>
      </MASH_STEPS>
    </MASH>
    <STYLE>
      <PROFILE>Aroma: Moderate sweetness (often with light notes of honey and/or vanilla) with light, grainy, spicy wheat aromatics, often with a bit of tartness. Moderate perfumy coriander, often with a complex herbal, spicy, or peppery note in the background. Moderate zesty, citrusy orangey fruitiness. A low spicy-herbal hop aroma is optional, but should never overpower the other characteristics. No diacetyl. Vegetal, celerylike, or ham-like aromas are inappropriate. Spices should blend in with fruity, floral and sweet aromas and should not be overly strong. Appearance: Very pale straw to very light gold in color. The beer will be very cloudy from starch haze and/or yeast, which gives it a milky, whitish-yellow appearance. Dense, white, moussy head. Head retention should be quite good. Flavor: Pleasant sweetness (often with a honey and/or vanilla character) and a zesty, orange-citrusy fruitiness. Refreshingly crisp with a dry, often tart, finish. Can have a low wheat flavor. Optionally has a very light lactic-tasting sourness. Herbalspicy flavors, which may include coriander and other spices, are common should be subtle and balanced, not overpowering. A spicy-earthy hop flavor is low to none, and if noticeable, never gets in the way of the spices. Hop bitterness is low to medium-low (as with a Hefeweizen), and doesn’t interfere with refreshing flavors of fruit and spice, nor does it persist into the finish. Bitterness from orange pith should not be present. Vegetal, celery-like, ham-like, or soapy flavors are inappropriate. No diacetyl. Mouthfeel: Medium-light to medium body, often having a smoothness and light creaminess from unmalted wheat and the occasional oats. Despite body and creaminess, finishes dry and often a bit tart. Effervescent character from high carbonation. Refreshing, from carbonation, light acidity, and lack of bitterness in finish. No harshness or astringency from orange pith. Should not be overly dry and thin, nor should it be thick and heavy.</PROFILE>
      <ABV_MIN>4.50000000</ABV_MIN>
      <CARB_MAX>0.00000000</CARB_MAX>
      <FG_MAX>1.01200000</FG_MAX>
      <IBU_MAX>20.00000000</IBU_MAX>
      <TYPE>Mixed</TYPE>
      <NAME>Witbier</NAME>
      <STYLE_GUIDE>BJCP 2008</STYLE_GUIDE>
      <OG_MIN>1.04400000</OG_MIN>
      <CATEGORY>Belgian and French Ale</CATEGORY>
      <OG_MAX>1.05200000</OG_MAX>
      <COLOR_MIN>2.00000000</COLOR_MIN>
      <ABV_MAX>5.50000000</ABV_MAX>
      <EXAMPLES>Hoegaarden Wit, St. Bernardus Blanche, Celis White, Vuuve 5, Brugs Tarwebier (Blanche de Bruges), Wittekerke, Allagash White, Blanche de Bruxelles, Ommegang Witte, Avery White Rascal, Unibroue Blanche de Chambly, Sterkens White Ale, Bell’s Winter White Ale, Victory Whirlwind Witbier, Hitachino Nest White Ale</EXAMPLES>
      <INGREDIENTS>About 50% unmalted wheat (traditionally soft white winter wheat) and 50% pale barley malt (usually Pils malt) constitute the grist. In some versions, up to 5-10% raw oats may be used. Spices of freshly-ground coriander and Curacao or sometimes sweet orange peel complement the sweet aroma and are quite characteristic. Other spices (e.g., chamomile, cumin, cinnamon, Grains of Paradise) may be used for complexity but are much less prominent. Ale yeast prone to the production of mild, spicy flavors is very characteristic. In some instances a very limited lactic fermentation, or the actual addition of lactic acid, is done.</INGREDIENTS>
      <FG_MIN>1.00800000</FG_MIN>
      <STYLE_LETTER>A</STYLE_LETTER>
      <VERSION>1</VERSION>
      <NOTES>A refreshing, elegant, tasty, moderatestrength wheat-based ale. A 400-year-old beer style that died out in the 1950s; it was later revived by Pierre Celis at Hoegaarden, and has grown steadily in popularity over time. The presence, character and degree of spicing and lactic sourness varies. Overly spiced and/or sour beers are not good examples of the style. Coriander of certain origins might give an inappropriate ham or celery character. The beer tends to be fragile and does not age well, so younger, fresher, properly handled examples are most desirable. Most examples seem to be approximately 5% ABV.</NOTES>
      <IBU_MIN>10.00000000</IBU_MIN>
      <CARB_MIN>0.00000000</CARB_MIN>
      <COLOR_MAX>4.00000000</COLOR_MAX>
      <CATEGORY_NUMBER>16</CATEGORY_NUMBER>
    </STYLE>
  </RECIPE>
  <RECIPE>
    <AGE>14</AGE>
    <FERMENTATION_STAGES>1</FERMENTATION_STAGES>
    <BATCH_SIZE>3.7854117891320316</BATCH_SIZE>
    <SECONDARY_TEMP>21.0</SECONDARY_TEMP>
    <TYPE>Extract</TYPE>
    <BOIL_SIZE>4.731764736415039</BOIL_SIZE>
    <TERTIARY_TEMP>21.0</TERTIARY_TEMP>
    <DISPLAY_OG>0.0</DISPLAY_OG>
    <NAME>Black Coffee Wheat</NAME>
    <FG>1.009</FG>
    <EQUIPMENT/>
    <SECONDARY_AGE>0</SECONDARY_AGE>
    <PRIMARY_AGE>14</PRIMARY_AGE>
    <OG>1.052</OG>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <PRIMARY_TEMP>21.0</PRIMARY_TEMP>
    <NOTES>Not sure if the hops were Hallertau or Hallertau Mittlefruh.
Exact weight of the hops to be measured</NOTES>
    <DISPLAY_FG>0.0</DISPLAY_FG>
    <BREWER/>
    <TERTIARY_AGE>0</TERTIARY_AGE>
    <BOIL_TIME>60</BOIL_TIME>
    <EFFICIENCY>100.0</EFFICIENCY>
    <HOPS>
      <HOP>
        <NAME>Hallertau</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <ALPHA>2.5</ALPHA>
        <AMOUNT>0.00793787</AMOUNT>
        <USE>Boil</USE>
        <TIME>45</TIME>
        <NOTES>No description</NOTES>
        <TYPE>Hop</TYPE>
        <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
      </HOP>
      <HOP>
        <NAME>Hallertau</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <ALPHA>2.5</ALPHA>
        <AMOUNT>0.00396893</AMOUNT>
        <USE>Boil</USE>
        <TIME>10</TIME>
        <NOTES>No description</NOTES>
        <TYPE>Hop</TYPE>
        <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
      </HOP>
    </HOPS>
    <FERMENTABLES>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Wheat DME</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Extract</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.3628739</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>93.04999999999984</YIELD>
        <COLOR>3.299999952316284</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Pilsen Light DME</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Extract</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.18143695</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>90.87999999999992</YIELD>
        <COLOR>1.899999976158142</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Carafa Special III</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Grain</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.0499092558983666</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>69.5652173913044</YIELD>
        <COLOR>500.0</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Chocolate Wheat Malt</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Grain</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.02494758</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>71.40999999999977</YIELD>
        <COLOR>400.0</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Crystal 80L</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Grain</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.02494758</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>73.5700000000001</YIELD>
        <COLOR>80.0</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
    </FERMENTABLES>
    <MISCS/>
    <YEASTS>
      <YEAST>
        <NAME>Safbrew WB-06</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Yeast</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.0</AMOUNT>
        <LABORATORY>Fermentis</LABORATORY>
        <PRODUCT_ID>WB-06</PRODUCT_ID>
        <MIN_TEMPERATURE>0</MIN_TEMPERATURE>
        <MAX_TEMPERATURE>0</MAX_TEMPERATURE>
        <ATTENUATION>80.0</ATTENUATION>
      </YEAST>
    </YEASTS>
    <WATERS/>
    <MASH>
      <TUN_WEIGHT>160.00000000</TUN_WEIGHT>
      <GRAIN_TEMP>22.22222220</GRAIN_TEMP>
      <VERSION>1</VERSION>
      <NAME>BIAB, Medium Body</NAME>
      <NOTES>Brew in a bag method where the full boil volume is mashed within the boil vessel and then the grains are withdrawn at the end of the mash.  No active sparging is required.  This is a medium body beer profile.</NOTES>
      <TUN_SPECIFIC_HEAT>0.30000000</TUN_SPECIFIC_HEAT>
      <EQUIP_ADJUST>FALSE</EQUIP_ADJUST>
      <TUN_TEMP>22.22222220</TUN_TEMP>
      <SPARGE_TEMP>75.60000000</SPARGE_TEMP>
      <PH>5.20000000</PH>
      <MASH_STEPS>
        <MASH_STEP>
          <RAMP_TIME>10.00000000</RAMP_TIME>
          <STEP_TEMP>66.70000000</STEP_TEMP>
          <INFUSE_AMOUNT>4.83156915</INFUSE_AMOUNT>
          <END_TIME>66.70000000</END_TIME>
          <STEP_TIME>75.00000000</STEP_TIME>
          <TYPE>Infusion</TYPE>
          <VERSION>1</VERSION>
          <NAME>Saccharification</NAME>
        </MASH_STEP>
        <MASH_STEP>
          <RAMP_TIME>7.00000000</RAMP_TIME>
          <STEP_TEMP>75.55555560</STEP_TEMP>
          <INFUSE_AMOUNT>0.00000000</INFUSE_AMOUNT>
          <END_TIME>75.55555560</END_TIME>
          <STEP_TIME>10.00000000</STEP_TIME>
          <TYPE>Temperature</TYPE>
          <VERSION>1</VERSION>
          <NAME>Mash Out</NAME>
        </MASH_STEP>
      </MASH_STEPS>
    </MASH>
    <STYLE>
      <PROFILE>Aroma: Moderate to strong phenols (usually clove) and fruity esters (usually banana). The balance and intensity of the phenol and ester components can vary but the best examples are reasonably balanced and fairly prominent. Optionally, a low to moderate vanilla character and/or low bubblegum notes may be present, but should not dominate. Noble hop character ranges from low to none. A light to moderate wheat aroma (which might be perceived as bready or grainy) may be present and is often accompanied by a caramel, bread crust, or richer malt aroma (e.g., from Vienna and/or Munich malt). Any malt character is supportive and does not overpower the yeast character. No diacetyl or DMS. A light tartness is optional but acceptable. Appearance: Light copper to mahogany brown in color. A very thick, moussy, long-lasting off-white head is characteristic. The high protein content of wheat impairs clarity in this traditionally unfiltered style, although the level of haze is somewhat variable. The suspended yeast sediment (which should be roused before drinking) also contributes to the cloudiness. Flavor: Low to moderately strong banana and clove flavor. The balance and intensity of the phenol and ester components can vary but the best examples are reasonably balanced and fairly prominent. Optionally, a very light to moderate vanilla character and/or low bubblegum notes can accentuate the banana flavor, sweetness and roundness; neither should be dominant if present. The soft, somewhat bready or grainy flavor of wheat is complementary, as is a richer caramel and/or melanoidin character from Munich and/or Vienna malt. The malty richness can be low to medium-high, but shouldn’t overpower the yeast character. A roasted malt character is inappropriate. Hop flavor is very low to none, and hop bitterness is very low to low. A tart, citrusy character from yeast and high carbonation is sometimes present, but typically muted. Well rounded, flavorful, often somewhat sweet palate with a relatively dry finish. No diacetyl or DMS. Mouthfeel: Medium-light to medium-full body. The texture of wheat as well as yeast in suspension imparts the sensation of a fluffy, creamy fullness that may progress to a lighter finish, aided by moderate to high carbonation. The presence of Munich and/or Vienna malts also provide an additional sense of richness and fullness. Effervescent.</PROFILE>
      <ABV_MIN>4.30000000</ABV_MIN>
      <CARB_MAX>0.00000000</CARB_MAX>
      <FG_MAX>1.01400000</FG_MAX>
      <IBU_MAX>18.00000000</IBU_MAX>
      <TYPE>Ale</TYPE>
      <NAME>Dunkelweizen</NAME>
      <STYLE_GUIDE>BJCP 2008</STYLE_GUIDE>
      <OG_MIN>1.04400000</OG_MIN>
      <CATEGORY>German Wheat and Rye Beer</CATEGORY>
      <OG_MAX>1.05600000</OG_MAX>
      <COLOR_MIN>14.00000000</COLOR_MIN>
      <ABV_MAX>5.60000000</ABV_MAX>
      <EXAMPLES>Weihenstephaner Hefeweissbier Dunkel, Ayinger Ur-Weisse, Franziskaner Dunkel Hefe-Weisse, Schneider Weisse (Original), Ettaler Weissbier Dunkel, Hacker-Pschorr Weisse Dark, Tucher Dunkles Hefe Weizen, Edelweiss Dunkel Weissbier, Erdinger Weissbier Dunkel, Kapuziner Weissbier Schwarz</EXAMPLES>
      <INGREDIENTS>By German law, at least 50% of the grist must be malted wheat, although some versions use up to 70%; the remainder is usually Munich and/or Vienna malt. A traditional decoction mash gives the appropriate body without cloying sweetness. Weizen ale yeasts produce the typical spicy and fruity character, although extreme fermentation temperatures can affect the balance and produce off-flavors. A small amount of noble hops are used only for bitterness.</INGREDIENTS>
      <FG_MIN>1.01000000</FG_MIN>
      <STYLE_LETTER>B</STYLE_LETTER>
      <VERSION>1</VERSION>
      <NOTES>A moderately dark, spicy, fruity, malty, refreshing wheat-based ale. Reflecting the best yeast and wheat character of a hefeweizen blended with the malty richness of a Munich dunkel. Old-fashioned Bavarian wheat beer was often dark. In the 1950s and 1960s, wheat beers did not have a youthful image, since most older people drank them for their healthgiving qualities. Today, the lighter hefeweizen is more common. The presence of Munich and/or Vienna-type barley malts gives this style a deep, rich barley malt character not found in a hefeweizen. Bottles with yeast are traditionally swirled or gently rolled prior to serving.</NOTES>
      <IBU_MIN>10.00000000</IBU_MIN>
      <CARB_MIN>0.00000000</CARB_MIN>
      <COLOR_MAX>23.00000000</COLOR_MAX>
      <CATEGORY_NUMBER>15</CATEGORY_NUMBER>
    </STYLE>
  </RECIPE>
  <RECIPE>
    <AGE>14</AGE>
    <FERMENTATION_STAGES>1</FERMENTATION_STAGES>
    <BATCH_SIZE>4.731764736415039</BATCH_SIZE>
    <SECONDARY_TEMP>21.0</SECONDARY_TEMP>
    <TYPE>Partial Mash</TYPE>
    <BOIL_SIZE>6.245929452067852</BOIL_SIZE>
    <TERTIARY_TEMP>21.0</TERTIARY_TEMP>
    <DISPLAY_OG>0.0</DISPLAY_OG>
    <NAME>Blueberry Wheat</NAME>
    <FG>1.007</FG>
    <EQUIPMENT/>
    <SECONDARY_AGE>0</SECONDARY_AGE>
    <PRIMARY_AGE>14</PRIMARY_AGE>
    <OG>1.056</OG>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <PRIMARY_TEMP>21.0</PRIMARY_TEMP>
    <NOTES/>
    <DISPLAY_FG>0.0</DISPLAY_FG>
    <BREWER/>
    <TERTIARY_AGE>0</TERTIARY_AGE>
    <BOIL_TIME>60</BOIL_TIME>
    <EFFICIENCY>75.0</EFFICIENCY>
    <HOPS>
      <HOP>
        <NAME>Nugget</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <ALPHA>14.2</ALPHA>
        <AMOUNT>9.9223E-4</AMOUNT>
        <USE>Boil</USE>
        <TIME>60</TIME>
        <NOTES>No description</NOTES>
        <TYPE>Hop</TYPE>
        <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
      </HOP>
      <HOP>
        <NAME>Saaz</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <ALPHA>2.2</ALPHA>
        <AMOUNT>0.0056699</AMOUNT>
        <USE>Boil</USE>
        <TIME>30</TIME>
        <NOTES>No description</NOTES>
        <TYPE>Hop</TYPE>
        <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
      </HOP>
      <HOP>
        <NAME>Saaz</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <ALPHA>2.2</ALPHA>
        <AMOUNT>0.00566990463296951</AMOUNT>
        <USE>First Wort</USE>
        <TIME>60</TIME>
        <NOTES>No description</NOTES>
        <TYPE>Hop</TYPE>
        <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
      </HOP>
    </HOPS>
    <FERMENTABLES>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Wheat Dry Extract</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Extract</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.6352087114337567</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>95.65217391304358</YIELD>
        <COLOR>8.0</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Barley, Flaked</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Grain</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.09071847</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>69.23999999999988</YIELD>
        <COLOR>1.7000000476837158</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Six-row (US)</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Grain</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.06803886</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>75.72999999999993</YIELD>
        <COLOR>1.7999999523162842</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
    </FERMENTABLES>
    <MISCS>
      <MISC>
        <AMOUNT_IS_WEIGHT>false</AMOUNT_IS_WEIGHT>
        <AMOUNT>0.29573500</AMOUNT>
        <USE_FOR>Boil</USE_FOR>
        <TYPE>Misc</TYPE>
        <VERSION>1</VERSION>
        <NOTES>Custom misc</NOTES>
        <NAME>Blueberries</NAME>
        <USE>Boil</USE>
        <DISPLAY_AMOUNT>10.0 oz</DISPLAY_AMOUNT>
        <DISPLAY_TIME>15 mins</DISPLAY_TIME>
      </MISC>
      <MISC>
        <AMOUNT_IS_WEIGHT>false</AMOUNT_IS_WEIGHT>
        <AMOUNT>0.29573500</AMOUNT>
        <USE_FOR>Boil</USE_FOR>
        <TYPE>Misc</TYPE>
        <VERSION>1</VERSION>
        <NOTES>Custom misc</NOTES>
        <NAME>Blueberries</NAME>
        <USE>Secondary</USE>
        <DISPLAY_AMOUNT>10.0 oz</DISPLAY_AMOUNT>
        <DISPLAY_TIME>10 days</DISPLAY_TIME>
      </MISC>
    </MISCS>
    <YEASTS>
      <YEAST>
        <NAME>Safbrew WB-06</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Yeast</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.0</AMOUNT>
        <LABORATORY>Fermentis</LABORATORY>
        <PRODUCT_ID>WB-06</PRODUCT_ID>
        <MIN_TEMPERATURE>0</MIN_TEMPERATURE>
        <MAX_TEMPERATURE>0</MAX_TEMPERATURE>
        <ATTENUATION>86.0</ATTENUATION>
      </YEAST>
    </YEASTS>
    <WATERS/>
    <MASH>
      <TUN_WEIGHT>160.00000000</TUN_WEIGHT>
      <GRAIN_TEMP>22.22222220</GRAIN_TEMP>
      <VERSION>1</VERSION>
      <NAME>BIAB, Medium Body</NAME>
      <NOTES>Brew in a bag method where the full boil volume is mashed within the boil vessel and then the grains are withdrawn at the end of the mash.  No active sparging is required.  This is a medium body beer profile.</NOTES>
      <TUN_SPECIFIC_HEAT>0.30000000</TUN_SPECIFIC_HEAT>
      <EQUIP_ADJUST>FALSE</EQUIP_ADJUST>
      <TUN_TEMP>22.22222220</TUN_TEMP>
      <SPARGE_TEMP>75.60000000</SPARGE_TEMP>
      <PH>5.20000000</PH>
      <MASH_STEPS>
        <MASH_STEP>
          <RAMP_TIME>10.00000000</RAMP_TIME>
          <STEP_TEMP>66.70000000</STEP_TEMP>
          <INFUSE_AMOUNT>6.40468678</INFUSE_AMOUNT>
          <END_TIME>66.70000000</END_TIME>
          <STEP_TIME>75.00000000</STEP_TIME>
          <TYPE>Infusion</TYPE>
          <VERSION>1</VERSION>
          <NAME>Saccharification</NAME>
        </MASH_STEP>
        <MASH_STEP>
          <RAMP_TIME>7.00000000</RAMP_TIME>
          <STEP_TEMP>75.55555560</STEP_TEMP>
          <INFUSE_AMOUNT>0.00000000</INFUSE_AMOUNT>
          <END_TIME>75.55555560</END_TIME>
          <STEP_TIME>10.00000000</STEP_TIME>
          <TYPE>Temperature</TYPE>
          <VERSION>1</VERSION>
          <NAME>Mash Out</NAME>
        </MASH_STEP>
      </MASH_STEPS>
    </MASH>
    <STYLE>
      <PROFILE>Aroma: Low to moderate grainy wheat or rye character. Some malty sweetness is acceptable. Esters can be moderate to none, although should reflect American yeast strains. The clove and banana aromas common to German hefeweizens are inappropriate. Hop aroma may be low to moderate, and can have either a citrusy American or a spicy or floral noble hop character. Slight crisp sharpness is optional. No diacetyl. Appearance: Usually pale yellow to gold. Clarity may range from brilliant to hazy with yeast approximating the German hefeweizen style of beer. Big, long-lasting white head. Flavor: Light to moderately strong grainy wheat or rye flavor, which can linger into the finish. Rye versions are richer and spicier than wheat. May have a moderate malty sweetness or finish quite dry. Low to moderate hop bitterness, which sometimes lasts into the finish. Low to moderate hop flavor (citrusy American or spicy/floral noble). Esters can be moderate to none, but should not take on a German Weizen character (banana). No clove phenols, although a light spiciness from wheat or rye is acceptable. May have a slightly crisp or sharp finish. No diacetyl. Mouthfeel: Medium-light to medium body. Medium-high to high carbonation. May have a light alcohol warmth in stronger examples.</PROFILE>
      <ABV_MIN>4.00000000</ABV_MIN>
      <CARB_MAX>0.00000000</CARB_MAX>
      <FG_MAX>1.01300000</FG_MAX>
      <IBU_MAX>30.00000000</IBU_MAX>
      <TYPE>Mixed</TYPE>
      <NAME>American Wheat or Rye Beer</NAME>
      <STYLE_GUIDE>BJCP 2008</STYLE_GUIDE>
      <OG_MIN>1.04000000</OG_MIN>
      <CATEGORY>Light Hybrid Beer</CATEGORY>
      <OG_MAX>1.05500000</OG_MAX>
      <COLOR_MIN>3.00000000</COLOR_MIN>
      <ABV_MAX>5.50000000</ABV_MAX>
      <EXAMPLES>Bell's Oberon, Harpoon UFO Hefeweizen, Three Floyds Gumballhead, Pyramid Hefe-Weizen, Widmer Hefeweizen, Sierra Nevada Unfiltered Wheat Beer, Anchor Summer Beer, Redhook Sunrye, Real Ale Full Moon Pale Rye</EXAMPLES>
      <INGREDIENTS>Clean American ale yeast, but also lager. up to 50+% wheat malt. American/noble hops. American Rye Beers can follow the same general guidelines, substituting rye for some or all of the wheat. Other base styles (e.g., IPA, stout) with a noticeable rye character should be entered in the Specialty Beer category (23).</INGREDIENTS>
      <FG_MIN>1.00800000</FG_MIN>
      <STYLE_LETTER>D</STYLE_LETTER>
      <VERSION>1</VERSION>
      <NOTES>Refreshing wheat or rye beers that can display more hop character and less yeast character than their German cousins. Different variations exist, from an easy-drinking fairly sweet beer to a dry, aggressively hopped beer with a strong wheat or rye flavor. Dark versions approximating dunkelweizens (with darker, richer malt flavors in addition to the color) should be entered in the Specialty Beer category. THE BREWER SHOULD SPECIFY IF RYE IS USED; IF NO DOMINANT GRAIN IS SPECIFIED, WHEAT WILL BE ASSUMED.</NOTES>
      <IBU_MIN>15.00000000</IBU_MIN>
      <CARB_MIN>0.00000000</CARB_MIN>
      <COLOR_MAX>6.00000000</COLOR_MAX>
      <CATEGORY_NUMBER>6</CATEGORY_NUMBER>
    </STYLE>
  </RECIPE>
  <RECIPE>
    <AGE>14</AGE>
    <FERMENTATION_STAGES>1</FERMENTATION_STAGES>
    <BATCH_SIZE>3.7854117891320316</BATCH_SIZE>
    <SECONDARY_TEMP>21.0</SECONDARY_TEMP>
    <TYPE>Extract</TYPE>
    <BOIL_SIZE>4.731764736415039</BOIL_SIZE>
    <TERTIARY_TEMP>21.0</TERTIARY_TEMP>
    <DISPLAY_OG>0.0</DISPLAY_OG>
    <NAME>Vanilla Bourbon Porter</NAME>
    <FG>1.016</FG>
    <EQUIPMENT/>
    <SECONDARY_AGE>0</SECONDARY_AGE>
    <PRIMARY_AGE>14</PRIMARY_AGE>
    <OG>1.067</OG>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <PRIMARY_TEMP>21.0</PRIMARY_TEMP>
    <NOTES>Results in higher ABV due to 50ml of 100 proof Bourbon and 10ml of 70 Proof Vanilla extract.
30ml per gallon of 0.8% ABV, bringing the total ABV to 8%</NOTES>
    <DISPLAY_FG>0.0</DISPLAY_FG>
    <BREWER/>
    <TERTIARY_AGE>0</TERTIARY_AGE>
    <BOIL_TIME>45</BOIL_TIME>
    <EFFICIENCY>100.0</EFFICIENCY>
    <HOPS>
      <HOP>
        <NAME>Chinook</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <ALPHA>11.5</ALPHA>
        <AMOUNT>0.00340194</AMOUNT>
        <USE>Boil</USE>
        <TIME>45</TIME>
        <NOTES>No description</NOTES>
        <TYPE>Hop</TYPE>
        <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
      </HOP>
      <HOP>
        <NAME>Willamette</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <ALPHA>4.5</ALPHA>
        <AMOUNT>0.00340194</AMOUNT>
        <USE>Boil</USE>
        <TIME>10</TIME>
        <NOTES>No description</NOTES>
        <TYPE>Hop</TYPE>
        <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
      </HOP>
    </HOPS>
    <FERMENTABLES>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Dark DME</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Extract</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.45359237</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>95.21000000000018</YIELD>
        <COLOR>18.0</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Wheat DME</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Extract</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.22679619</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>93.04999999999984</YIELD>
        <COLOR>3.299999952316284</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Chocolate Malt (British)</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Grain</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.07484274</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>73.5700000000001</YIELD>
        <COLOR>475.0</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Black Patent (British)</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Grain</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.03855535</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>58.42000000000008</YIELD>
        <COLOR>525.0</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Crystal 70-80L (British)</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Grain</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.03855535</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>73.5700000000001</YIELD>
        <COLOR>75.0</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
    </FERMENTABLES>
    <MISCS>
      <MISC>
        <AMOUNT_IS_WEIGHT>false</AMOUNT_IS_WEIGHT>
        <AMOUNT>0.00985785</AMOUNT>
        <USE_FOR>Secondary</USE_FOR>
        <TYPE>Misc</TYPE>
        <VERSION>1</VERSION>
        <NOTES>Custom misc</NOTES>
        <NAME>Vanilla Extract</NAME>
        <USE>Secondary</USE>
        <DISPLAY_AMOUNT>1.9999999999999998 tsp</DISPLAY_AMOUNT>
        <DISPLAY_TIME>15 days</DISPLAY_TIME>
      </MISC>
      <MISC>
        <AMOUNT_IS_WEIGHT>false</AMOUNT_IS_WEIGHT>
        <AMOUNT>0.01478675</AMOUNT>
        <USE_FOR>Secondary</USE_FOR>
        <TYPE>Misc</TYPE>
        <VERSION>1</VERSION>
        <NOTES>Custom misc</NOTES>
        <NAME>Oak Cubes</NAME>
        <USE>Secondary</USE>
        <DISPLAY_AMOUNT>0.5 oz</DISPLAY_AMOUNT>
        <DISPLAY_TIME>15 days</DISPLAY_TIME>
      </MISC>
      <MISC>
        <AMOUNT_IS_WEIGHT>false</AMOUNT_IS_WEIGHT>
        <AMOUNT>0.04436025</AMOUNT>
        <USE_FOR>Secondary</USE_FOR>
        <TYPE>Misc</TYPE>
        <VERSION>1</VERSION>
        <NOTES>Custom misc</NOTES>
        <NAME>Bourbon</NAME>
        <USE>Secondary</USE>
        <DISPLAY_AMOUNT>1.5 oz</DISPLAY_AMOUNT>
        <DISPLAY_TIME>15 days</DISPLAY_TIME>
      </MISC>
    </MISCS>
    <YEASTS>
      <YEAST>
        <NAME>Safale S-04</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Yeast</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.05</AMOUNT>
        <LABORATORY>Fermentis</LABORATORY>
        <PRODUCT_ID>S-04</PRODUCT_ID>
        <MIN_TEMPERATURE>17</MIN_TEMPERATURE>
        <MAX_TEMPERATURE>17</MAX_TEMPERATURE>
        <ATTENUATION>75.0</ATTENUATION>
      </YEAST>
    </YEASTS>
    <WATERS/>
    <MASH>
      <TUN_WEIGHT>0.00000000</TUN_WEIGHT>
      <GRAIN_TEMP>20.00000000</GRAIN_TEMP>
      <VERSION>1</VERSION>
      <NAME>New Mash Profile</NAME>
      <NOTES/>
      <TUN_SPECIFIC_HEAT>0.00000000</TUN_SPECIFIC_HEAT>
      <EQUIP_ADJUST>FALSE</EQUIP_ADJUST>
      <TUN_TEMP>20.00000000</TUN_TEMP>
      <SPARGE_TEMP>75.55550000</SPARGE_TEMP>
      <PH>7.00000000</PH>
      <MASH_STEPS/>
    </MASH>
    <STYLE>
      <PROFILE>Aroma: Roasty aroma (often with a lightly burnt, black malt character) should be noticeable and may be moderately strong. Optionally may also show some additional malt character in support (grainy, bready, toffee-like, caramelly, chocolate, coffee, rich, and/or sweet). Hop aroma low to high (US or UK varieties). Some American versions may be dry-hopped. Fruity esters are moderate to none. Diacetyl low to none. Appearance: Medium brown to very dark brown, often with ruby- or garnet-like highlights. Can approach black in color. Clarity may be difficult to discern in such a dark beer, but when not opaque will be clear (particularly when held up to the light). Full, tan-colored head with moderately good head retention. Flavor: Moderately strong malt flavor usually features a lightly burnt, black malt character (and sometimes chocolate and/or coffee flavors) with a bit of roasty dryness in the finish. Overall flavor may finish from dry to medium-sweet, depending on grist composition, hop bittering level, and attenuation. May have a sharp character from dark roasted grains, although should not be overly acrid, burnt or harsh. Medium to high bitterness, which can be accentuated by the roasted malt. Hop flavor can vary from low to moderately high (US or UK varieties, typically), and balances the roasted malt flavors. Diacetyl low to none. Fruity esters moderate to none. Mouthfeel: Medium to medium-full body. Moderately low to moderately high carbonation. Stronger versions may have a slight alcohol warmth. May have a slight astringency from roasted grains, although this character should not be strong.</PROFILE>
      <ABV_MIN>4.80000000</ABV_MIN>
      <CARB_MAX>0.00000000</CARB_MAX>
      <FG_MAX>1.01600000</FG_MAX>
      <IBU_MAX>50.00000000</IBU_MAX>
      <TYPE>Ale</TYPE>
      <NAME>Robust Porter</NAME>
      <STYLE_GUIDE>BJCP 2008</STYLE_GUIDE>
      <OG_MIN>1.04800000</OG_MIN>
      <CATEGORY>Porter</CATEGORY>
      <OG_MAX>1.06500000</OG_MAX>
      <COLOR_MIN>22.00000000</COLOR_MIN>
      <ABV_MAX>6.50000000</ABV_MAX>
      <EXAMPLES>Great Lakes Edmund Fitzgerald Porter, Meantime London Porter, Anchor Porter, Smuttynose Robust Porter, Sierra Nevada Porter, Deschutes Black Butte Porter, Boulevard Bully! Porter, Rogue Mocha Porter, Avery New World Porter, Bell’s Porter, Great Divide Saint Bridget’s Porter</EXAMPLES>
      <INGREDIENTS>May contain several malts, prominently dark roasted malts and grains, which often include black patent malt (chocolate malt and/or roasted barley may also be used in some versions). Hops are used for bittering, flavor and/or aroma, and are frequently UK or US varieties. Water with moderate to high carbonate hardness is typical. Ale yeast can either be clean US versions or characterful English varieties.</INGREDIENTS>
      <FG_MIN>1.01200000</FG_MIN>
      <STYLE_LETTER>B</STYLE_LETTER>
      <VERSION>1</VERSION>
      <NOTES>A substantial, malty dark ale with a complex and flavorful roasty character. Stronger, hoppier and/or roastier version of porter designed as either a historical throwback or an American interpretation of the style. Traditional versions will have a more subtle hop character (often English), while modern versions may be considerably more aggressive. Both types are equally valid. Although a rather broad style open to brewer interpretation, it may be distinguished from Stout as lacking a strong roasted barley character. It differs from a brown porter in that a black patent or roasted grain character is usually present, and it can be stronger in alcohol. Roast intensity and malt flavors can also vary significantly. May or may not have a strong hop character, and may or may not have significant fermentation by-products; thus may seem to have an “American” or “English” character.</NOTES>
      <IBU_MIN>25.00000000</IBU_MIN>
      <CARB_MIN>0.00000000</CARB_MIN>
      <COLOR_MAX>35.00000000</COLOR_MAX>
      <CATEGORY_NUMBER>12</CATEGORY_NUMBER>
    </STYLE>
  </RECIPE>
  <RECIPE>
    <AGE>14</AGE>
    <FERMENTATION_STAGES>1</FERMENTATION_STAGES>
    <BATCH_SIZE>3.7854117891320316</BATCH_SIZE>
    <SECONDARY_TEMP>21.0</SECONDARY_TEMP>
    <TYPE>Extract</TYPE>
    <BOIL_SIZE>4.731764736415039</BOIL_SIZE>
    <TERTIARY_TEMP>21.0</TERTIARY_TEMP>
    <DISPLAY_OG>0.0</DISPLAY_OG>
    <NAME>Centennial/Cascade IPA</NAME>
    <FG>1.012</FG>
    <EQUIPMENT/>
    <SECONDARY_AGE>0</SECONDARY_AGE>
    <PRIMARY_AGE>14</PRIMARY_AGE>
    <OG>1.067</OG>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <PRIMARY_TEMP>21.0</PRIMARY_TEMP>
    <NOTES/>
    <DISPLAY_FG>0.0</DISPLAY_FG>
    <BREWER/>
    <TERTIARY_AGE>0</TERTIARY_AGE>
    <BOIL_TIME>60</BOIL_TIME>
    <EFFICIENCY>100.0</EFFICIENCY>
    <HOPS>
      <HOP>
        <NAME>Centennial</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <ALPHA>7.6</ALPHA>
        <AMOUNT>0.00425243</AMOUNT>
        <USE>Boil</USE>
        <TIME>60</TIME>
        <NOTES>No description</NOTES>
        <TYPE>Hop</TYPE>
        <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
      </HOP>
      <HOP>
        <NAME>Cascade</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <ALPHA>6.9</ALPHA>
        <AMOUNT>0.00652039</AMOUNT>
        <USE>Boil</USE>
        <TIME>25</TIME>
        <NOTES>No description</NOTES>
        <TYPE>Hop</TYPE>
        <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
      </HOP>
      <HOP>
        <NAME>Centennial</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <ALPHA>7.6</ALPHA>
        <AMOUNT>0.0056699</AMOUNT>
        <USE>Boil</USE>
        <TIME>10</TIME>
        <NOTES>No description</NOTES>
        <TYPE>Hop</TYPE>
        <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
      </HOP>
      <HOP>
        <NAME>Cascade</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <ALPHA>6.9</ALPHA>
        <AMOUNT>0.00850486</AMOUNT>
        <USE>Boil</USE>
        <TIME>5</TIME>
        <NOTES>No description</NOTES>
        <TYPE>Hop</TYPE>
        <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
      </HOP>
      <HOP>
        <NAME>Centennial</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <ALPHA>7.6</ALPHA>
        <AMOUNT>0.01133980926593902</AMOUNT>
        <USE>Dry Hop</USE>
        <TIME>7</TIME>
        <NOTES>No description</NOTES>
        <TYPE>Hop</TYPE>
        <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
      </HOP>
    </HOPS>
    <FERMENTABLES>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Pilsen Light DME</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Extract</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.45359237</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>90.87999999999992</YIELD>
        <COLOR>1.899999976158142</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Golden Light DME</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Extract</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.15875733</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>93.04999999999984</YIELD>
        <COLOR>4.699999809265137</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Honey</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Sugar</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.06803886</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>75.72999999999993</YIELD>
        <COLOR>1.5</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Cane Sugar</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Sugar</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.04535924</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>99.5399999999999</YIELD>
        <COLOR>0.0</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Crystal 80L</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Grain</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.03401943</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>73.5700000000001</YIELD>
        <COLOR>80.0</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
    </FERMENTABLES>
    <MISCS>
      <MISC>
        <AMOUNT_IS_WEIGHT>false</AMOUNT_IS_WEIGHT>
        <AMOUNT>0.00591470</AMOUNT>
        <USE_FOR>Sweet orange flavor</USE_FOR>
        <TYPE>Misc</TYPE>
        <VERSION>1</VERSION>
        <NOTES>Adds a sweet flavor and aroma, reminiscent of Grand Marnier.</NOTES>
        <NAME>Orange Peel, Sweet</NAME>
        <USE>Boil</USE>
        <DISPLAY_AMOUNT>0.2 oz</DISPLAY_AMOUNT>
        <DISPLAY_TIME>5 mins</DISPLAY_TIME>
      </MISC>
    </MISCS>
    <YEASTS>
      <YEAST>
        <NAME>Safale US-05</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Yeast</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.0</AMOUNT>
        <LABORATORY>Fermentis</LABORATORY>
        <PRODUCT_ID>US-05</PRODUCT_ID>
        <MIN_TEMPERATURE>0</MIN_TEMPERATURE>
        <MAX_TEMPERATURE>0</MAX_TEMPERATURE>
        <ATTENUATION>80.0</ATTENUATION>
      </YEAST>
    </YEASTS>
    <WATERS/>
    <MASH>
      <TUN_WEIGHT>160.00000000</TUN_WEIGHT>
      <GRAIN_TEMP>22.22222220</GRAIN_TEMP>
      <VERSION>1</VERSION>
      <NAME>BIAB, Medium Body</NAME>
      <NOTES>Brew in a bag method where the full boil volume is mashed within the boil vessel and then the grains are withdrawn at the end of the mash.  No active sparging is required.  This is a medium body beer profile.</NOTES>
      <TUN_SPECIFIC_HEAT>0.30000000</TUN_SPECIFIC_HEAT>
      <EQUIP_ADJUST>FALSE</EQUIP_ADJUST>
      <TUN_TEMP>22.22222220</TUN_TEMP>
      <SPARGE_TEMP>75.60000000</SPARGE_TEMP>
      <PH>5.20000000</PH>
      <MASH_STEPS>
        <MASH_STEP>
          <RAMP_TIME>10.00000000</RAMP_TIME>
          <STEP_TEMP>66.70000000</STEP_TEMP>
          <INFUSE_AMOUNT>4.76578417</INFUSE_AMOUNT>
          <END_TIME>66.70000000</END_TIME>
          <STEP_TIME>75.00000000</STEP_TIME>
          <TYPE>Infusion</TYPE>
          <VERSION>1</VERSION>
          <NAME>Saccharification</NAME>
        </MASH_STEP>
        <MASH_STEP>
          <RAMP_TIME>7.00000000</RAMP_TIME>
          <STEP_TEMP>75.55555560</STEP_TEMP>
          <INFUSE_AMOUNT>0.00000000</INFUSE_AMOUNT>
          <END_TIME>75.55555560</END_TIME>
          <STEP_TIME>10.00000000</STEP_TIME>
          <TYPE>Temperature</TYPE>
          <VERSION>1</VERSION>
          <NAME>Mash Out</NAME>
        </MASH_STEP>
      </MASH_STEPS>
    </MASH>
    <STYLE>
      <PROFILE>Aroma: A prominent to intense hop aroma with a citrusy, floral, perfume-like, resinous, piney, and/or fruity character derived from American hops. Many versions are dry hopped and can have an additional grassy aroma, although this is not required. Some clean malty sweetness may be found in the background, but should be at a lower level than in English examples. Fruitiness, either from esters or hops, may also be detected in some versions, although a neutral fermentation character is also acceptable. Some alcohol may be noted. Appearance: Color ranges from medium gold to medium reddish copper; some versions can have an orange-ish tint. Should be clear, although unfiltered dry-hopped versions may be a bit hazy. Good head stand with white to off-white color should persist. Flavor: Hop flavor is medium to high, and should reflect an American hop character with citrusy, floral, resinous, piney or fruity aspects. Medium-high to very high hop bitterness, although the malt backbone will support the strong hop character and provide the best balance. Malt flavor should be low to medium, and is generally clean and malty sweet although some caramel or toasty flavors are acceptable at low levels. No diacetyl. Low fruitiness is acceptable but not required. The bitterness may linger into the aftertaste but should not be harsh. Medium-dry to dry finish. Some clean alcohol flavor can be noted in stronger versions. Oak is inappropriate in this style. May be slightly sulfury, but most examples do not exhibit this character. Mouthfeel: Smooth, medium-light to medium-bodied mouthfeel without hop-derived astringency, although moderate to medium-high carbonation can combine to render an overall dry sensation in the presence of malt sweetness. Some smooth alcohol warming can and should be sensed in stronger (but not all) versions. Body is generally less than in English counterparts.</PROFILE>
      <ABV_MIN>5.50000000</ABV_MIN>
      <CARB_MAX>0.00000000</CARB_MAX>
      <FG_MAX>1.01800000</FG_MAX>
      <IBU_MAX>70.00000000</IBU_MAX>
      <TYPE>Ale</TYPE>
      <NAME>American IPA</NAME>
      <STYLE_GUIDE>BJCP 2008</STYLE_GUIDE>
      <OG_MIN>1.05600000</OG_MIN>
      <CATEGORY>India Pale Ale (IPA)</CATEGORY>
      <OG_MAX>1.07500000</OG_MAX>
      <COLOR_MIN>6.00000000</COLOR_MIN>
      <ABV_MAX>7.50000000</ABV_MAX>
      <EXAMPLES>Bell’s Two-Hearted Ale, AleSmith IPA, Russian River Blind Pig IPA, Stone IPA, Three Floyds Alpha King, Great Divide Titan IPA, Bear Republic Racer 5 IPA, Victory Hop Devil, Sierra Nevada Celebration Ale, Anderson Valley Hop Ottin’, Dogfish Head 60 Minute IPA, Founder’s Centennial IPA, Anchor Liberty Ale, Harpoon IPA, Avery IPA</EXAMPLES>
      <INGREDIENTS>Pale ale malt (well-modified and suitable for single-temperature infusion mashing); American hops; American yeast that can give a clean or slightly fruity profile. Generally all-malt, but mashed at lower temperatures for high attenuation. Water character varies from soft to moderately sulfate. Versions with a noticeable Rye character (“RyePA”) should be entered in the Specialty category.</INGREDIENTS>
      <FG_MIN>1.01000000</FG_MIN>
      <STYLE_LETTER>B</STYLE_LETTER>
      <VERSION>1</VERSION>
      <NOTES>A decidedly hoppy and bitter, moderately strong American pale ale. An American version of the historical English style, brewed using American ingredients and attitude.</NOTES>
      <IBU_MIN>40.00000000</IBU_MIN>
      <CARB_MIN>0.00000000</CARB_MIN>
      <COLOR_MAX>15.00000000</COLOR_MAX>
      <CATEGORY_NUMBER>14</CATEGORY_NUMBER>
    </STYLE>
  </RECIPE>
  <RECIPE>
    <AGE>14</AGE>
    <FERMENTATION_STAGES>1</FERMENTATION_STAGES>
    <BATCH_SIZE>4.731764736415039</BATCH_SIZE>
    <SECONDARY_TEMP>21.0</SECONDARY_TEMP>
    <TYPE>Partial Mash</TYPE>
    <BOIL_SIZE>6.624470630981055</BOIL_SIZE>
    <TERTIARY_TEMP>21.0</TERTIARY_TEMP>
    <DISPLAY_OG>0.0</DISPLAY_OG>
    <NAME>Double Chocolate Milk Stout</NAME>
    <FG>1.01</FG>
    <EQUIPMENT/>
    <SECONDARY_AGE>0</SECONDARY_AGE>
    <PRIMARY_AGE>14</PRIMARY_AGE>
    <OG>1.053</OG>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <PRIMARY_TEMP>21.0</PRIMARY_TEMP>
    <NOTES/>
    <DISPLAY_FG>0.0</DISPLAY_FG>
    <BREWER/>
    <TERTIARY_AGE>0</TERTIARY_AGE>
    <BOIL_TIME>60</BOIL_TIME>
    <EFFICIENCY>75.0</EFFICIENCY>
    <HOPS>
      <HOP>
        <NAME>Nugget</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <ALPHA>14.1</ALPHA>
        <AMOUNT>0.00283495</AMOUNT>
        <USE>Boil</USE>
        <TIME>60</TIME>
        <NOTES>No description</NOTES>
        <TYPE>Hop</TYPE>
        <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
      </HOP>
      <HOP>
        <NAME>Goldings, East Kent</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <ALPHA>5.0</ALPHA>
        <AMOUNT>0.0042524284747271325</AMOUNT>
        <USE>First Wort</USE>
        <TIME>60</TIME>
        <NOTES>Floral, earthy, slightly sweet, spicy. Used for: British Ales</NOTES>
        <TYPE>Hop</TYPE>
        <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
      </HOP>
      <HOP>
        <NAME>Goldings, East Kent</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <ALPHA>5.0</ALPHA>
        <AMOUNT>0.002834952316484755</AMOUNT>
        <USE>Boil</USE>
        <TIME>5</TIME>
        <NOTES>Floral, earthy, slightly sweet, spicy. Used for: British Ales</NOTES>
        <TYPE>Hop</TYPE>
        <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
      </HOP>
    </HOPS>
    <FERMENTABLES>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Pilsen DME</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Extract</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.22686025408348456</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>91.30434782608704</YIELD>
        <COLOR>1.899999976158142</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Barley, Flaked</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Grain</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.11339809</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>69.23999999999988</YIELD>
        <COLOR>1.7000000476837158</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Chocolate Wheat Malt</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Grain</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.11339809</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>71.40999999999977</YIELD>
        <COLOR>375.0</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Crystal 80L</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Grain</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.11339809</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>73.5700000000001</YIELD>
        <COLOR>80.0</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Milk Sugar</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Sugar</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.11339809</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>75.72999999999993</YIELD>
        <COLOR>0.0</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Six-row (US)</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Grain</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.09071847</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>75.72999999999993</YIELD>
        <COLOR>1.7999999523162842</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Wheat Dry Extract</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Extract</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.11343012704174228</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>95.65217391304358</YIELD>
        <COLOR>8.0</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Carafa Special III</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Grain</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.03176043557168784</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>69.5652173913044</YIELD>
        <COLOR>525.0</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
    </FERMENTABLES>
    <MISCS>
      <MISC>
        <AMOUNT_IS_WEIGHT>false</AMOUNT_IS_WEIGHT>
        <AMOUNT>0.02957350</AMOUNT>
        <USE_FOR>Boil</USE_FOR>
        <TYPE>Misc</TYPE>
        <VERSION>1</VERSION>
        <NOTES>Custom misc</NOTES>
        <NAME>Chocolate Bittersweet</NAME>
        <USE>Boil</USE>
        <DISPLAY_AMOUNT>1.0 oz</DISPLAY_AMOUNT>
        <DISPLAY_TIME>10 mins</DISPLAY_TIME>
      </MISC>
      <MISC>
        <AMOUNT_IS_WEIGHT>false</AMOUNT_IS_WEIGHT>
        <AMOUNT>0.02957350</AMOUNT>
        <USE_FOR>Boil</USE_FOR>
        <TYPE>Misc</TYPE>
        <VERSION>1</VERSION>
        <NOTES>Custom misc</NOTES>
        <NAME>Cacao Nibs</NAME>
        <USE>Secondary</USE>
        <DISPLAY_AMOUNT>1.0 oz</DISPLAY_AMOUNT>
        <DISPLAY_TIME>15 days</DISPLAY_TIME>
      </MISC>
    </MISCS>
    <YEASTS>
      <YEAST>
        <NAME>Safale US-05</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Yeast</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.02</AMOUNT>
        <LABORATORY>Fermentis</LABORATORY>
        <PRODUCT_ID>US-05</PRODUCT_ID>
        <MIN_TEMPERATURE>18</MIN_TEMPERATURE>
        <MAX_TEMPERATURE>18</MAX_TEMPERATURE>
        <ATTENUATION>80.0</ATTENUATION>
      </YEAST>
    </YEASTS>
    <WATERS/>
    <MASH>
      <TUN_WEIGHT>160.00000000</TUN_WEIGHT>
      <GRAIN_TEMP>22.22222220</GRAIN_TEMP>
      <VERSION>1</VERSION>
      <NAME>BIAB, Full Body</NAME>
      <NOTES>Brew in a bag method where the full boil volume is mashed within the boil vessel and then the grains are withdrawn at the end of the mash.  No active sparging is required. This is a full body beer profile.</NOTES>
      <TUN_SPECIFIC_HEAT>0.30000000</TUN_SPECIFIC_HEAT>
      <EQUIP_ADJUST>FALSE</EQUIP_ADJUST>
      <TUN_TEMP>22.22222220</TUN_TEMP>
      <SPARGE_TEMP>75.60000000</SPARGE_TEMP>
      <PH>5.20000000</PH>
      <MASH_STEPS>
        <MASH_STEP>
          <RAMP_TIME>10.00000000</RAMP_TIME>
          <STEP_TEMP>68.90000000</STEP_TEMP>
          <INFUSE_AMOUNT>7.08714381</INFUSE_AMOUNT>
          <END_TIME>68.90000000</END_TIME>
          <STEP_TIME>60.00000000</STEP_TIME>
          <TYPE>Infusion</TYPE>
          <VERSION>1</VERSION>
          <NAME>Saccharification</NAME>
        </MASH_STEP>
        <MASH_STEP>
          <RAMP_TIME>7.00000000</RAMP_TIME>
          <STEP_TEMP>75.55555560</STEP_TEMP>
          <INFUSE_AMOUNT>0.00000000</INFUSE_AMOUNT>
          <END_TIME>75.55555560</END_TIME>
          <STEP_TIME>10.00000000</STEP_TIME>
          <TYPE>Temperature</TYPE>
          <VERSION>1</VERSION>
          <NAME>Mash Out</NAME>
        </MASH_STEP>
      </MASH_STEPS>
    </MASH>
    <STYLE>
      <PROFILE/>
      <ABV_MIN>0.00000000</ABV_MIN>
      <CARB_MAX>0.00000000</CARB_MAX>
      <FG_MAX>1.02300000</FG_MAX>
      <IBU_MAX>40.00000000</IBU_MAX>
      <TYPE/>
      <NAME>Milk Stout</NAME>
      <STYLE_GUIDE/>
      <OG_MIN>1.04200000</OG_MIN>
      <CATEGORY/>
      <OG_MAX>1.05600000</OG_MAX>
      <COLOR_MIN>30.00000000</COLOR_MIN>
      <ABV_MAX>100.00000000</ABV_MAX>
      <EXAMPLES/>
      <INGREDIENTS/>
      <FG_MIN>1.01000000</FG_MIN>
      <STYLE_LETTER/>
      <VERSION>1</VERSION>
      <NOTES/>
      <IBU_MIN>25.00000000</IBU_MIN>
      <CARB_MIN>0.00000000</CARB_MIN>
      <COLOR_MAX>40.00000000</COLOR_MAX>
      <CATEGORY_NUMBER/>
    </STYLE>
  </RECIPE>
  <RECIPE>
    <AGE>14</AGE>
    <FERMENTATION_STAGES>1</FERMENTATION_STAGES>
    <BATCH_SIZE>4.731764736415039</BATCH_SIZE>
    <SECONDARY_TEMP>21.0</SECONDARY_TEMP>
    <TYPE>Partial Mash</TYPE>
    <BOIL_SIZE>5.678117683698047</BOIL_SIZE>
    <TERTIARY_TEMP>21.0</TERTIARY_TEMP>
    <DISPLAY_OG>0.0</DISPLAY_OG>
    <NAME>Dubbel Trouble</NAME>
    <FG>1.01</FG>
    <EQUIPMENT/>
    <SECONDARY_AGE>0</SECONDARY_AGE>
    <PRIMARY_AGE>14</PRIMARY_AGE>
    <OG>1.062</OG>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <PRIMARY_TEMP>21.0</PRIMARY_TEMP>
    <NOTES/>
    <DISPLAY_FG>0.0</DISPLAY_FG>
    <BREWER/>
    <TERTIARY_AGE>0</TERTIARY_AGE>
    <BOIL_TIME>60</BOIL_TIME>
    <EFFICIENCY>75.0</EFFICIENCY>
    <HOPS>
      <HOP>
        <NAME>Perle</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <ALPHA>8.3</ALPHA>
        <AMOUNT>0.00283495</AMOUNT>
        <USE>Boil</USE>
        <TIME>60</TIME>
        <NOTES>No description</NOTES>
        <TYPE>Hop</TYPE>
        <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
      </HOP>
      <HOP>
        <NAME>Hersbrucker</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <ALPHA>3.5</ALPHA>
        <AMOUNT>0.0056699</AMOUNT>
        <USE>Boil</USE>
        <TIME>15</TIME>
        <NOTES>No description</NOTES>
        <TYPE>Hop</TYPE>
        <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
      </HOP>
      <HOP>
        <NAME>Saaz</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <ALPHA>2.9</ALPHA>
        <AMOUNT>0.0056699</AMOUNT>
        <USE>Boil</USE>
        <TIME>10</TIME>
        <NOTES>No description</NOTES>
        <TYPE>Hop</TYPE>
        <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
      </HOP>
    </HOPS>
    <FERMENTABLES>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Pilsen Light DME</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Extract</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.56699047</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>90.87999999999992</YIELD>
        <COLOR>1.899999976158142</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Two-row (US)</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Grain</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.11339809</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>80.06000000000016</YIELD>
        <COLOR>1.7999999523162842</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Candi Sugar, Dark (Belgian)</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Sugar</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.09074410163339383</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>78.26086956521745</YIELD>
        <COLOR>120.0</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Special "B" (Belgian)</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Grain</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.06803886</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>64.9200000000002</YIELD>
        <COLOR>150.0</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Wheat DME</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Extract</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.09074410163339383</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>80.43478260869549</YIELD>
        <COLOR>3.0</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
    </FERMENTABLES>
    <MISCS/>
    <YEASTS>
      <YEAST>
        <NAME>Safbrew BE-256</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Yeast</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.05</AMOUNT>
        <LABORATORY>Fermentis</LABORATORY>
        <PRODUCT_ID>BE-256</PRODUCT_ID>
        <MIN_TEMPERATURE>17</MIN_TEMPERATURE>
        <MAX_TEMPERATURE>17</MAX_TEMPERATURE>
        <ATTENUATION>82.0</ATTENUATION>
      </YEAST>
    </YEASTS>
    <WATERS/>
    <MASH>
      <TUN_WEIGHT>160.00000000</TUN_WEIGHT>
      <GRAIN_TEMP>22.22222220</GRAIN_TEMP>
      <VERSION>1</VERSION>
      <NAME>BIAB, Medium Body</NAME>
      <NOTES>Brew in a bag method where the full boil volume is mashed within the boil vessel and then the grains are withdrawn at the end of the mash.  No active sparging is required.  This is a medium body beer profile.</NOTES>
      <TUN_SPECIFIC_HEAT>0.30000000</TUN_SPECIFIC_HEAT>
      <EQUIP_ADJUST>FALSE</EQUIP_ADJUST>
      <TUN_TEMP>22.22222220</TUN_TEMP>
      <SPARGE_TEMP>75.60000000</SPARGE_TEMP>
      <PH>5.20000000</PH>
      <MASH_STEPS>
        <MASH_STEP>
          <RAMP_TIME>10.00000000</RAMP_TIME>
          <STEP_TEMP>66.70000000</STEP_TEMP>
          <INFUSE_AMOUNT>5.85955463</INFUSE_AMOUNT>
          <END_TIME>66.70000000</END_TIME>
          <STEP_TIME>75.00000000</STEP_TIME>
          <TYPE>Infusion</TYPE>
          <VERSION>1</VERSION>
          <NAME>Saccharification</NAME>
        </MASH_STEP>
        <MASH_STEP>
          <RAMP_TIME>7.00000000</RAMP_TIME>
          <STEP_TEMP>75.55555560</STEP_TEMP>
          <INFUSE_AMOUNT>0.00000000</INFUSE_AMOUNT>
          <END_TIME>75.55555560</END_TIME>
          <STEP_TIME>10.00000000</STEP_TIME>
          <TYPE>Temperature</TYPE>
          <VERSION>1</VERSION>
          <NAME>Mash Out</NAME>
        </MASH_STEP>
      </MASH_STEPS>
    </MASH>
    <STYLE>
      <PROFILE>Aroma: Complex, rich malty sweetness; malt may have hints of chocolate, caramel and/or toast (but never roasted or burnt aromas). Moderate fruity esters (usually including raisins and plums, sometimes also dried cherries). Esters sometimes include banana or apple. Spicy phenols and higher alcohols are common (may include light clove and spice, peppery, rose-like and/or perfumy notes). Spicy qualities can be moderate to very low. Alcohol, if present, is soft and never hot or solventy. A small number of examples may include a low noble hop aroma, but hops are usually absent. No diacetyl. Appearance: Dark amber to copper in color, with an attractive reddish depth of color. Generally clear. Large, dense, and longlasting creamy off-white head. Flavor: Similar qualities as aroma. Rich, complex medium to medium-full malty sweetness on the palate yet finishes moderately dry. Complex malt, ester, alcohol and phenol interplay (raisiny flavors are common; dried fruit flavors are welcome; clove-like spiciness is optional). Balance is always toward the malt. Medium-low bitterness that doesn’t persist into the finish. Low noble hop flavor is optional and not usually present. No diacetyl. Should not be as malty as a bock and should not have crystal malt-type sweetness. No spices. Mouthfeel: Medium-full body. Medium-high carbonation, which can influence the perception of body. Low alcohol warmth. Smooth, never hot or solventy.</PROFILE>
      <ABV_MIN>6.00000000</ABV_MIN>
      <CARB_MAX>0.00000000</CARB_MAX>
      <FG_MAX>1.01800000</FG_MAX>
      <IBU_MAX>25.00000000</IBU_MAX>
      <TYPE>Ale</TYPE>
      <NAME>Belgian Dubbel</NAME>
      <STYLE_GUIDE>BJCP 2008</STYLE_GUIDE>
      <OG_MIN>1.06200000</OG_MIN>
      <CATEGORY>Belgian Strong Ale</CATEGORY>
      <OG_MAX>1.07500000</OG_MAX>
      <COLOR_MIN>10.00000000</COLOR_MIN>
      <ABV_MAX>7.60000000</ABV_MAX>
      <EXAMPLES>Westmalle Dubbel, St. Bernardus Pater 6, La Trappe Dubbel, Corsendonk Abbey Brown Ale, Grimbergen Double, Affligem Dubbel, Chimay Premiere (Red), Pater Lieven Bruin, Duinen Dubbel, St. Feuillien Brune, New Belgium Abbey Belgian Style Ale, Stoudts Abbey Double Ale, Russian River Benediction, Flying Fish Dubbel, Lost Abbey Lost and Found Abbey Ale, Allagash Double</EXAMPLES>
      <INGREDIENTS>Belgian yeast strains prone to production of higher alcohols, esters, and phenolics are commonly used. Water can be soft to hard. Impression of complex grain bill, although traditional versions are typically Belgian Pils malt with caramelized sugar syrup or other unrefined sugars providing much of the character. Homebrewers may use Belgian Pils or pale base malt, Munich-type malts for maltiness, Special B for raisin flavors, CaraVienne or CaraMunich for dried fruit flavors, other specialty grains for character. Dark caramelized sugar syrup or sugars for color and rum-raisin flavors. Noble-type, English-type or Styrian Goldings hops commonly used. No spices are traditionally used, although restrained use is allowable.</INGREDIENTS>
      <FG_MIN>1.00800000</FG_MIN>
      <STYLE_LETTER>B</STYLE_LETTER>
      <VERSION>1</VERSION>
      <NOTES>A deep reddish, moderately strong, malty, complex Belgian ale. Originated at monasteries in the Middle Ages, and was revived in the mid-1800s after the Napoleonic era. Most commercial examples are in the 6.5 – 7% ABV range. Traditionally bottle-conditioned (“refermented in the bottle”).</NOTES>
      <IBU_MIN>15.00000000</IBU_MIN>
      <CARB_MIN>0.00000000</CARB_MIN>
      <COLOR_MAX>17.00000000</COLOR_MAX>
      <CATEGORY_NUMBER>18</CATEGORY_NUMBER>
    </STYLE>
  </RECIPE>
  <RECIPE>
    <AGE>14</AGE>
    <FERMENTATION_STAGES>1</FERMENTATION_STAGES>
    <BATCH_SIZE>4.731764736415039</BATCH_SIZE>
    <SECONDARY_TEMP>21.0</SECONDARY_TEMP>
    <TYPE>Partial Mash</TYPE>
    <BOIL_SIZE>6.624470630981055</BOIL_SIZE>
    <TERTIARY_TEMP>21.0</TERTIARY_TEMP>
    <DISPLAY_OG>0.0</DISPLAY_OG>
    <NAME>German Red Ale</NAME>
    <FG>1.008</FG>
    <EQUIPMENT/>
    <SECONDARY_AGE>0</SECONDARY_AGE>
    <PRIMARY_AGE>14</PRIMARY_AGE>
    <OG>1.048</OG>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <PRIMARY_TEMP>21.0</PRIMARY_TEMP>
    <NOTES/>
    <DISPLAY_FG>0.0</DISPLAY_FG>
    <BREWER/>
    <TERTIARY_AGE>0</TERTIARY_AGE>
    <BOIL_TIME>60</BOIL_TIME>
    <EFFICIENCY>75.0</EFFICIENCY>
    <HOPS>
      <HOP>
        <NAME>Hersbrucker</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <ALPHA>3.5</ALPHA>
        <AMOUNT>0.0056699</AMOUNT>
        <USE>Boil</USE>
        <TIME>60</TIME>
        <NOTES>No description</NOTES>
        <TYPE>Hop</TYPE>
        <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
      </HOP>
      <HOP>
        <NAME>Perle</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <ALPHA>8.3</ALPHA>
        <AMOUNT>0.00283495</AMOUNT>
        <USE>Boil</USE>
        <TIME>60</TIME>
        <NOTES>No description</NOTES>
        <TYPE>Hop</TYPE>
        <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
      </HOP>
      <HOP>
        <NAME>Hersbrucker</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <ALPHA>3.5</ALPHA>
        <AMOUNT>0.0056699</AMOUNT>
        <USE>Boil</USE>
        <TIME>5</TIME>
        <NOTES>No description</NOTES>
        <TYPE>Hop</TYPE>
        <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
      </HOP>
    </HOPS>
    <FERMENTABLES>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Pilsen DME</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Extract</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.38555352</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>90.87999999999992</YIELD>
        <COLOR>1.899999976158142</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Munich (German)</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Grain</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.14968548</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>80.06000000000016</YIELD>
        <COLOR>8.0</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Honey Malt (Canadian)</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Grain</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.09071847</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>64.9200000000002</YIELD>
        <COLOR>18.0</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Six-row (US)</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Grain</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.09071847</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>75.72999999999993</YIELD>
        <COLOR>1.7999999523162842</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Special "B" (Belgian)</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Grain</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.07484274</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>64.9200000000002</YIELD>
        <COLOR>160.0</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Biscuit (Belgian)</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Grain</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.03628739</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>75.72999999999993</YIELD>
        <COLOR>24.0</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
    </FERMENTABLES>
    <MISCS/>
    <YEASTS>
      <YEAST>
        <NAME>Safale K-97</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Yeast</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.05</AMOUNT>
        <LABORATORY>Fermentis</LABORATORY>
        <PRODUCT_ID>K-97</PRODUCT_ID>
        <MIN_TEMPERATURE>17</MIN_TEMPERATURE>
        <MAX_TEMPERATURE>17</MAX_TEMPERATURE>
        <ATTENUATION>81.0</ATTENUATION>
      </YEAST>
    </YEASTS>
    <WATERS/>
    <MASH>
      <TUN_WEIGHT>160.00000000</TUN_WEIGHT>
      <GRAIN_TEMP>22.22222220</GRAIN_TEMP>
      <VERSION>1</VERSION>
      <NAME>BIAB, Medium Body</NAME>
      <NOTES>Brew in a bag method where the full boil volume is mashed within the boil vessel and then the grains are withdrawn at the end of the mash.  No active sparging is required.  This is a medium body beer profile.</NOTES>
      <TUN_SPECIFIC_HEAT>0.30000000</TUN_SPECIFIC_HEAT>
      <EQUIP_ADJUST>FALSE</EQUIP_ADJUST>
      <TUN_TEMP>22.22222220</TUN_TEMP>
      <SPARGE_TEMP>75.60000000</SPARGE_TEMP>
      <PH>5.20000000</PH>
      <MASH_STEPS>
        <MASH_STEP>
          <RAMP_TIME>10.00000000</RAMP_TIME>
          <STEP_TEMP>66.70000000</STEP_TEMP>
          <INFUSE_AMOUNT>7.06672318</INFUSE_AMOUNT>
          <END_TIME>66.70000000</END_TIME>
          <STEP_TIME>75.00000000</STEP_TIME>
          <TYPE>Infusion</TYPE>
          <VERSION>1</VERSION>
          <NAME>Saccharification</NAME>
        </MASH_STEP>
        <MASH_STEP>
          <RAMP_TIME>7.00000000</RAMP_TIME>
          <STEP_TEMP>75.55555560</STEP_TEMP>
          <INFUSE_AMOUNT>0.00000000</INFUSE_AMOUNT>
          <END_TIME>75.55555560</END_TIME>
          <STEP_TIME>10.00000000</STEP_TIME>
          <TYPE>Temperature</TYPE>
          <VERSION>1</VERSION>
          <NAME>Mash Out</NAME>
        </MASH_STEP>
      </MASH_STEPS>
    </MASH>
    <STYLE>
      <PROFILE>Aroma: Low to moderate hop aroma from dry hopping or late kettle additions of American hop varieties. A citrusy hop character is common, but not required. Moderately low to moderately high maltiness balances and sometimes masks the hop presentation, and usually shows a moderate caramel character. Esters vary from moderate to none. No diacetyl. Appearance: Amber to coppery brown in color. Moderately large off-white head with good retention. Generally quite clear, although dry-hopped versions may be slightly hazy. Flavor: Moderate to high hop flavor from American hop varieties, which often but not always has a citrusy quality. Malt flavors are moderate to strong, and usually show an initial malty sweetness followed by a moderate caramel flavor (and sometimes other character malts in lesser amounts). Malt and hop bitterness are usually balanced and mutually supportive. Fruity esters can be moderate to none. Caramel sweetness and hop flavor/bitterness can linger somewhat into the medium to full finish. No diacetyl. Mouthfeel: Medium to medium-full body. Carbonation moderate to high. Overall smooth finish without astringency often associated with high hopping rates. Stronger versions may have a slight alcohol warmth.</PROFILE>
      <ABV_MIN>4.50000000</ABV_MIN>
      <CARB_MAX>0.00000000</CARB_MAX>
      <FG_MAX>1.01500000</FG_MAX>
      <IBU_MAX>40.00000000</IBU_MAX>
      <TYPE>Ale</TYPE>
      <NAME>American Amber Ale</NAME>
      <STYLE_GUIDE>BJCP 2008</STYLE_GUIDE>
      <OG_MIN>1.04500000</OG_MIN>
      <CATEGORY>American Ale</CATEGORY>
      <OG_MAX>1.06000000</OG_MAX>
      <COLOR_MIN>10.00000000</COLOR_MIN>
      <ABV_MAX>6.20000000</ABV_MAX>
      <EXAMPLES>North Coast Red Seal Ale, Troegs HopBack Amber Ale, Deschutes Cinder Cone Red, Pyramid Broken Rake, St. Rogue Red Ale, Anderson Valley Boont Amber Ale, Lagunitas Censored Ale, Avery Redpoint Ale, McNeill's Firehouse Amber Ale, Mendocino Red Tail Ale, Bell's Amber</EXAMPLES>
      <INGREDIENTS>Pale ale malt, typically American two-row. Medium to dark crystal malts. May contain specialty grains which add character and uniqueness. American hops, often with citrusy flavors, are common but others may also be used. Water can vary in sulfate &amp; carbonate content.</INGREDIENTS>
      <FG_MIN>1.01000000</FG_MIN>
      <STYLE_LETTER>B</STYLE_LETTER>
      <VERSION>1</VERSION>
      <NOTES>Like an American pale ale with more body, more caramel richness, and a balance more towards malt than hops (although hop rates can be significant). Known simply as Red Ales in some regions, these beers were popularized in the hop-loving Northern California and the Pacific Northwest areas before spreading nationwide. Can overlap in color with American pale ales. However, American amber ales differ from American pale ales not only by being usually darker in color, but also by having more caramel flavor, more body, and usually being balanced more evenly between malt and bitterness. Should not have a strong chocolate or roast character that might suggest an American brown ale (although small amounts are OK).</NOTES>
      <IBU_MIN>25.00000000</IBU_MIN>
      <CARB_MIN>0.00000000</CARB_MIN>
      <COLOR_MAX>17.00000000</COLOR_MAX>
      <CATEGORY_NUMBER>10</CATEGORY_NUMBER>
    </STYLE>
  </RECIPE>
  <RECIPE>
    <AGE>14</AGE>
    <FERMENTATION_STAGES>1</FERMENTATION_STAGES>
    <BATCH_SIZE>3.7854117891320316</BATCH_SIZE>
    <SECONDARY_TEMP>21.0</SECONDARY_TEMP>
    <TYPE>Partial Mash</TYPE>
    <BOIL_SIZE>4.731764736415039</BOIL_SIZE>
    <TERTIARY_TEMP>21.0</TERTIARY_TEMP>
    <DISPLAY_OG>0.0</DISPLAY_OG>
    <NAME>Honey Ginger Ale</NAME>
    <FG>1.015</FG>
    <EQUIPMENT/>
    <SECONDARY_AGE>0</SECONDARY_AGE>
    <PRIMARY_AGE>14</PRIMARY_AGE>
    <OG>1.052</OG>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <PRIMARY_TEMP>21.0</PRIMARY_TEMP>
    <NOTES>Partial mash:
Heat 128 oz water for mashing. Used additional 20oz for getting the water to mash temperature.
Strike temperature: 164F
Mash temperature used: 152-154

Used 16oz of sparge water at 170F.

The water was short by 16oz. So added additional water.

1.034 without honey at 30 min boil point.

Over powered by ginger. Over carbonation.</NOTES>
    <DISPLAY_FG>0.0</DISPLAY_FG>
    <BREWER/>
    <TERTIARY_AGE>0</TERTIARY_AGE>
    <BOIL_TIME>60</BOIL_TIME>
    <EFFICIENCY>75.0</EFFICIENCY>
    <HOPS>
      <HOP>
        <NAME>Cascade</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <ALPHA>6.6</ALPHA>
        <AMOUNT>0.00708738</AMOUNT>
        <USE>Boil</USE>
        <TIME>60</TIME>
        <NOTES>No description</NOTES>
        <TYPE>Hop</TYPE>
        <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
      </HOP>
    </HOPS>
    <FERMENTABLES>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Golden Light DME</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Extract</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.29483504</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>90.87999999999992</YIELD>
        <COLOR>4.699999809265137</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Two-row (Canadian)</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Grain</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.13607771</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>77.89999999999982</YIELD>
        <COLOR>2.0999999046325684</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Crystal 80L</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Grain</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.09071847</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>73.5700000000001</YIELD>
        <COLOR>80.0</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Honey</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Sugar</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.09071847</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>75.72999999999993</YIELD>
        <COLOR>1.5</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Honey Malt (Canadian)</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Grain</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.09071847</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>64.9200000000002</YIELD>
        <COLOR>25.0</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
    </FERMENTABLES>
    <MISCS>
      <MISC>
        <AMOUNT_IS_WEIGHT>false</AMOUNT_IS_WEIGHT>
        <AMOUNT>0.02957350</AMOUNT>
        <USE_FOR>Ginger flavor</USE_FOR>
        <TYPE>Misc</TYPE>
        <VERSION>1</VERSION>
        <NOTES>Contributes ginger flavor. Add during the boil.</NOTES>
        <NAME>Ginger Root</NAME>
        <USE>Boil</USE>
        <DISPLAY_AMOUNT>1.0 oz</DISPLAY_AMOUNT>
        <DISPLAY_TIME>5 mins</DISPLAY_TIME>
      </MISC>
      <MISC>
        <AMOUNT_IS_WEIGHT>false</AMOUNT_IS_WEIGHT>
        <AMOUNT>0.02957350</AMOUNT>
        <USE_FOR>Ginger flavor</USE_FOR>
        <TYPE>Misc</TYPE>
        <VERSION>1</VERSION>
        <NOTES>Contributes ginger flavor. Add during the boil.</NOTES>
        <NAME>Ginger Root</NAME>
        <USE>Secondary</USE>
        <DISPLAY_AMOUNT>1.0 oz</DISPLAY_AMOUNT>
        <DISPLAY_TIME>7 days</DISPLAY_TIME>
      </MISC>
    </MISCS>
    <YEASTS>
      <YEAST>
        <NAME>Dry Ale Yeast</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Yeast</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.0</AMOUNT>
        <LABORATORY>Muntons</LABORATORY>
        <PRODUCT_ID>Standard Ale Yeast</PRODUCT_ID>
        <MIN_TEMPERATURE>0</MIN_TEMPERATURE>
        <MAX_TEMPERATURE>0</MAX_TEMPERATURE>
        <ATTENUATION>70.0</ATTENUATION>
      </YEAST>
    </YEASTS>
    <WATERS/>
    <MASH>
      <TUN_WEIGHT>160.00000000</TUN_WEIGHT>
      <GRAIN_TEMP>22.22222220</GRAIN_TEMP>
      <VERSION>1</VERSION>
      <NAME>BIAB, Medium Body</NAME>
      <NOTES>Brew in a bag method where the full boil volume is mashed within the boil vessel and then the grains are withdrawn at the end of the mash.  No active sparging is required.  This is a medium body beer profile.</NOTES>
      <TUN_SPECIFIC_HEAT>0.30000000</TUN_SPECIFIC_HEAT>
      <EQUIP_ADJUST>FALSE</EQUIP_ADJUST>
      <TUN_TEMP>22.22222220</TUN_TEMP>
      <SPARGE_TEMP>75.60000000</SPARGE_TEMP>
      <PH>5.20000000</PH>
      <MASH_STEPS>
        <MASH_STEP>
          <RAMP_TIME>10.00000000</RAMP_TIME>
          <STEP_TEMP>66.70000000</STEP_TEMP>
          <INFUSE_AMOUNT>5.04927939</INFUSE_AMOUNT>
          <END_TIME>66.70000000</END_TIME>
          <STEP_TIME>75.00000000</STEP_TIME>
          <TYPE>Infusion</TYPE>
          <VERSION>1</VERSION>
          <NAME>Saccharification</NAME>
        </MASH_STEP>
        <MASH_STEP>
          <RAMP_TIME>7.00000000</RAMP_TIME>
          <STEP_TEMP>75.55555560</STEP_TEMP>
          <INFUSE_AMOUNT>0.00000000</INFUSE_AMOUNT>
          <END_TIME>75.55555560</END_TIME>
          <STEP_TIME>10.00000000</STEP_TIME>
          <TYPE>Temperature</TYPE>
          <VERSION>1</VERSION>
          <NAME>Mash Out</NAME>
        </MASH_STEP>
      </MASH_STEPS>
    </MASH>
    <STYLE>
      <PROFILE>Aroma: Low to moderate hop aroma from dry hopping or late kettle additions of American hop varieties. A citrusy hop character is common, but not required. Moderately low to moderately high maltiness balances and sometimes masks the hop presentation, and usually shows a moderate caramel character. Esters vary from moderate to none. No diacetyl. Appearance: Amber to coppery brown in color. Moderately large off-white head with good retention. Generally quite clear, although dry-hopped versions may be slightly hazy. Flavor: Moderate to high hop flavor from American hop varieties, which often but not always has a citrusy quality. Malt flavors are moderate to strong, and usually show an initial malty sweetness followed by a moderate caramel flavor (and sometimes other character malts in lesser amounts). Malt and hop bitterness are usually balanced and mutually supportive. Fruity esters can be moderate to none. Caramel sweetness and hop flavor/bitterness can linger somewhat into the medium to full finish. No diacetyl. Mouthfeel: Medium to medium-full body. Carbonation moderate to high. Overall smooth finish without astringency often associated with high hopping rates. Stronger versions may have a slight alcohol warmth.</PROFILE>
      <ABV_MIN>4.50000000</ABV_MIN>
      <CARB_MAX>0.00000000</CARB_MAX>
      <FG_MAX>1.01500000</FG_MAX>
      <IBU_MAX>40.00000000</IBU_MAX>
      <TYPE>Ale</TYPE>
      <NAME>American Amber Ale</NAME>
      <STYLE_GUIDE>BJCP 2008</STYLE_GUIDE>
      <OG_MIN>1.04500000</OG_MIN>
      <CATEGORY>American Ale</CATEGORY>
      <OG_MAX>1.06000000</OG_MAX>
      <COLOR_MIN>10.00000000</COLOR_MIN>
      <ABV_MAX>6.20000000</ABV_MAX>
      <EXAMPLES>North Coast Red Seal Ale, Troegs HopBack Amber Ale, Deschutes Cinder Cone Red, Pyramid Broken Rake, St. Rogue Red Ale, Anderson Valley Boont Amber Ale, Lagunitas Censored Ale, Avery Redpoint Ale, McNeill's Firehouse Amber Ale, Mendocino Red Tail Ale, Bell's Amber</EXAMPLES>
      <INGREDIENTS>Pale ale malt, typically American two-row. Medium to dark crystal malts. May contain specialty grains which add character and uniqueness. American hops, often with citrusy flavors, are common but others may also be used. Water can vary in sulfate &amp; carbonate content.</INGREDIENTS>
      <FG_MIN>1.01000000</FG_MIN>
      <STYLE_LETTER>B</STYLE_LETTER>
      <VERSION>1</VERSION>
      <NOTES>Like an American pale ale with more body, more caramel richness, and a balance more towards malt than hops (although hop rates can be significant). Known simply as Red Ales in some regions, these beers were popularized in the hop-loving Northern California and the Pacific Northwest areas before spreading nationwide. Can overlap in color with American pale ales. However, American amber ales differ from American pale ales not only by being usually darker in color, but also by having more caramel flavor, more body, and usually being balanced more evenly between malt and bitterness. Should not have a strong chocolate or roast character that might suggest an American brown ale (although small amounts are OK).</NOTES>
      <IBU_MIN>25.00000000</IBU_MIN>
      <CARB_MIN>0.00000000</CARB_MIN>
      <COLOR_MAX>17.00000000</COLOR_MAX>
      <CATEGORY_NUMBER>10</CATEGORY_NUMBER>
    </STYLE>
  </RECIPE>
  <RECIPE>
    <AGE>14</AGE>
    <FERMENTATION_STAGES>1</FERMENTATION_STAGES>
    <BATCH_SIZE>3.7854117891320316</BATCH_SIZE>
    <SECONDARY_TEMP>21.0</SECONDARY_TEMP>
    <TYPE>Extract</TYPE>
    <BOIL_SIZE>4.731764736415039</BOIL_SIZE>
    <TERTIARY_TEMP>21.0</TERTIARY_TEMP>
    <DISPLAY_OG>0.0</DISPLAY_OG>
    <NAME>Honey Orange Wheat Ale</NAME>
    <FG>1.007</FG>
    <EQUIPMENT/>
    <SECONDARY_AGE>0</SECONDARY_AGE>
    <PRIMARY_AGE>14</PRIMARY_AGE>
    <OG>1.056</OG>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <PRIMARY_TEMP>21.0</PRIMARY_TEMP>
    <NOTES>Orange squash into secondary.</NOTES>
    <DISPLAY_FG>0.0</DISPLAY_FG>
    <BREWER/>
    <TERTIARY_AGE>0</TERTIARY_AGE>
    <BOIL_TIME>60</BOIL_TIME>
    <EFFICIENCY>100.0</EFFICIENCY>
    <HOPS>
      <HOP>
        <NAME>Cascade</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <ALPHA>6.9</ALPHA>
        <AMOUNT>0.0059534</AMOUNT>
        <USE>Boil</USE>
        <TIME>30</TIME>
        <NOTES>No description</NOTES>
        <TYPE>Hop</TYPE>
        <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
      </HOP>
      <HOP>
        <NAME>Cascade</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <ALPHA>6.9</ALPHA>
        <AMOUNT>0.00311845</AMOUNT>
        <USE>Boil</USE>
        <TIME>15</TIME>
        <NOTES>No description</NOTES>
        <TYPE>Hop</TYPE>
        <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
      </HOP>
    </HOPS>
    <FERMENTABLES>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Wheat DME</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Extract</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.31751466</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>93.04999999999984</YIELD>
        <COLOR>3.299999952316284</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Pilsen Light DME</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Extract</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.27215542</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>90.87999999999992</YIELD>
        <COLOR>1.899999976158142</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Honey Malt (Canadian)</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Grain</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.04989516</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>64.9200000000002</YIELD>
        <COLOR>18.0</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
    </FERMENTABLES>
    <MISCS>
      <MISC>
        <AMOUNT_IS_WEIGHT>false</AMOUNT_IS_WEIGHT>
        <AMOUNT>0.00975926</AMOUNT>
        <USE_FOR/>
        <TYPE>Misc</TYPE>
        <VERSION>1</VERSION>
        <NOTES>11g</NOTES>
        <NAME>Orange Peel, Sweet</NAME>
        <USE>Boil</USE>
        <DISPLAY_AMOUNT>0.33 oz</DISPLAY_AMOUNT>
        <DISPLAY_TIME>5 mins</DISPLAY_TIME>
      </MISC>
      <MISC>
        <AMOUNT_IS_WEIGHT>false</AMOUNT_IS_WEIGHT>
        <AMOUNT>4.00000000</AMOUNT>
        <USE_FOR>Secondary</USE_FOR>
        <TYPE>Misc</TYPE>
        <VERSION>1</VERSION>
        <NOTES>Custom misc</NOTES>
        <NAME>Orange Zest</NAME>
        <USE>Secondary</USE>
        <DISPLAY_AMOUNT>4.0 items</DISPLAY_AMOUNT>
        <DISPLAY_TIME>60 days</DISPLAY_TIME>
      </MISC>
      <MISC>
        <AMOUNT_IS_WEIGHT>false</AMOUNT_IS_WEIGHT>
        <AMOUNT>4.00000000</AMOUNT>
        <USE_FOR>Secondary</USE_FOR>
        <TYPE>Misc</TYPE>
        <VERSION>1</VERSION>
        <NOTES>Custom misc</NOTES>
        <NAME>Oranges</NAME>
        <USE>Secondary</USE>
        <DISPLAY_AMOUNT>4.0 items</DISPLAY_AMOUNT>
        <DISPLAY_TIME>60 days</DISPLAY_TIME>
      </MISC>
      <MISC>
        <AMOUNT_IS_WEIGHT>false</AMOUNT_IS_WEIGHT>
        <AMOUNT>0.01478675</AMOUNT>
        <USE_FOR>Nutty, citrus flavor</USE_FOR>
        <TYPE>Misc</TYPE>
        <VERSION>1</VERSION>
        <NOTES>Contributes a nutty, citrus flavor.</NOTES>
        <NAME>Coriander Seed</NAME>
        <USE>Boil</USE>
        <DISPLAY_AMOUNT>0.5 oz</DISPLAY_AMOUNT>
        <DISPLAY_TIME>10 mins</DISPLAY_TIME>
      </MISC>
    </MISCS>
    <YEASTS>
      <YEAST>
        <NAME>Safbrew WB-06</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Yeast</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.03</AMOUNT>
        <LABORATORY>Fermentis</LABORATORY>
        <PRODUCT_ID>WB-06</PRODUCT_ID>
        <MIN_TEMPERATURE>0</MIN_TEMPERATURE>
        <MAX_TEMPERATURE>0</MAX_TEMPERATURE>
        <ATTENUATION>86.0</ATTENUATION>
      </YEAST>
    </YEASTS>
    <WATERS/>
    <MASH>
      <TUN_WEIGHT>160.00000000</TUN_WEIGHT>
      <GRAIN_TEMP>22.22222220</GRAIN_TEMP>
      <VERSION>1</VERSION>
      <NAME>BIAB, Medium Body</NAME>
      <NOTES>Brew in a bag method where the full boil volume is mashed within the boil vessel and then the grains are withdrawn at the end of the mash.  No active sparging is required.  This is a medium body beer profile.</NOTES>
      <TUN_SPECIFIC_HEAT>0.30000000</TUN_SPECIFIC_HEAT>
      <EQUIP_ADJUST>FALSE</EQUIP_ADJUST>
      <TUN_TEMP>22.22222220</TUN_TEMP>
      <SPARGE_TEMP>75.60000000</SPARGE_TEMP>
      <PH>5.20000000</PH>
      <MASH_STEPS>
        <MASH_STEP>
          <RAMP_TIME>10.00000000</RAMP_TIME>
          <STEP_TEMP>66.70000000</STEP_TEMP>
          <INFUSE_AMOUNT>4.78165990</INFUSE_AMOUNT>
          <END_TIME>66.70000000</END_TIME>
          <STEP_TIME>75.00000000</STEP_TIME>
          <TYPE>Infusion</TYPE>
          <VERSION>1</VERSION>
          <NAME>Saccharification</NAME>
        </MASH_STEP>
        <MASH_STEP>
          <RAMP_TIME>7.00000000</RAMP_TIME>
          <STEP_TEMP>75.55555560</STEP_TEMP>
          <INFUSE_AMOUNT>0.00000000</INFUSE_AMOUNT>
          <END_TIME>75.55555560</END_TIME>
          <STEP_TIME>10.00000000</STEP_TIME>
          <TYPE>Temperature</TYPE>
          <VERSION>1</VERSION>
          <NAME>Mash Out</NAME>
        </MASH_STEP>
      </MASH_STEPS>
    </MASH>
    <STYLE>
      <PROFILE>Aroma: Variable. Most exhibit varying amounts of fruity esters, spicy phenols and/or yeast-borne aromatics. Aromas from actual spice additions may be present. Hop aroma may be none to high, and may include a dry-hopped character. Malt aroma may be low to high, and may include character of non-barley grains such as wheat or rye. Some may include aromas of Belgian microbiota, most commonly Brettanomyces and/or Lactobacillus. No diacetyl. Appearance: Variable. Color varies considerably from pale gold to very dark. Clarity may be hazy to clear. Head retention is usually good. Generally moderate to high carbonation. Flavor: Variable. A great variety of flavors are found in these beers. Maltiness may be light to quite rich. Hop flavor and bitterness may be low to high. Spicy flavors may be imparted by yeast (phenolics) and/or actual spice additions. May include characteristics of grains other than barley, such as wheat or rye. May include flavors produced by Belgian microbiota such as Brettanomyces or Lactobacillus. May include flavors from adjuncts such as caramelized sugar syrup or honey. Mouthfeel: Variable. Some are well-attenuated, thus fairly light-bodied for their original gravity, while others are thick and rich. Most are moderately to highly carbonated. A warming sensation from alcohol may be present in stronger examples. A “mouth puckering” sensation may be present from acidity.</PROFILE>
      <ABV_MIN>3.00000000</ABV_MIN>
      <CARB_MAX>0.00000000</CARB_MAX>
      <FG_MAX>1.01900000</FG_MAX>
      <IBU_MAX>40.00000000</IBU_MAX>
      <TYPE>Ale</TYPE>
      <NAME>Belgian Specialty Ale</NAME>
      <STYLE_GUIDE>BJCP 2008</STYLE_GUIDE>
      <OG_MIN>1.03000000</OG_MIN>
      <CATEGORY>Belgian and French Ale</CATEGORY>
      <OG_MAX>1.08000000</OG_MAX>
      <COLOR_MIN>3.00000000</COLOR_MIN>
      <ABV_MAX>9.00000000</ABV_MAX>
      <EXAMPLES>Orval; De Dolle’s Arabier, Oerbier, Boskeun and Stille Nacht; La Chouffe, McChouffe, Chouffe Bok and N’ice Chouffe; Ellezelloise Hercule Stout and Quintine Amber; Unibroue Ephemere, Maudite, Don de Dieu, etc.; Minty; Zatte Bie; Caracole Amber, Saxo and Nostradamus; Silenrieu Sara and Joseph; Fantome Black Ghost and Speciale Noel; Dupont Moinette, Moinette Brune, and Avec Les Bons Voeux de la Brasserie Dupont; St. Fullien Noel; Gouden Carolus Noel; Affligem Noel; Guldenburg and Pere Noel; De Ranke XX Bitter and Guldenberg; Poperings Hommelbier; Bush (Scaldis); Moinette Brune; Grottenbier; La Trappe Quadrupel; Weyerbacher QUAD; Biere de Miel; Verboden Vrucht; New Belgium 1554 Black Ale; Cantillon Iris; Russian River Temptation; Lost Abbey Cuvee de Tomme and Devotion, Lindemans Kriek and Framboise, and many more</EXAMPLES>
      <INGREDIENTS>May include herbs and/or spices. May include unusual grains and malts, though the grain character should be apparent if it is a key ingredient. May include adjuncts such as caramelized sugar syrup and honey. May include Belgian microbiota such as Brettanomyces or Lactobacillus. Unusual techniques, such as blending, may be used through primarily to arrive at a particular result. The process alone does not make a beer unique to a blind judging panel if the final product does not taste different.</INGREDIENTS>
      <FG_MIN>1.00600000</FG_MIN>
      <STYLE_LETTER>E</STYLE_LETTER>
      <VERSION>1</VERSION>
      <NOTES>Variable. This category encompasses a wide range of Belgian ales produced by truly artisanal brewers more concerned with creating unique products than in increasing sales. Unique beers of small, independent Belgian breweries that have come to enjoy local popularity but may be far less well-known outside of their own regions. Many have attained “cult status” in the U.S. (and other parts of the world) and now owe a significant portion of their sales to export. This is a catch-all category for any Belgian-style beer not fitting any other Belgian style category. The category can be used for clones of specific beers (e.g., Orval, La Chouffe); to produce a beer fitting a broader style that doesn’t have its own category; or to create an artisanal or experimental beer of the brewer’s own choosing (e.g., strong Belgian golden ale with spices, something unique). Creativity is the only limit in brewing but the entrants must identify what is special about their entry. This category may be used as an “incubator” for recognized styles for which there is not yet a formal BJCP category. Some styles falling into this classification include: • Blond Trappist table beer • Artisanal Blond • Artisanal Amber • Artisanal Brown • Belgian-style Barleywines • Trappist Quadrupels • Belgian Spiced Christmas Beers • Belgian Stout • Belgian IPA • Strong and/or Dark Saison • Fruit-based Flanders Red/Brown The judges must understand the brewer’s intent in order to properly judge an entry in this category. THE BREWER MUST SPECIFY EITHER THE BEER BEING CLONED, THE NEW STYLE BEING PRODUCED OR THE SPECIAL INGREDIENTS OR PROCESSES USED. Additional background information on the style and/or beer may be provided to judges to assist in the judging, including style parameters or detailed descriptions of the beer. Beers fitting other Belgian categories should not be entered in this category.</NOTES>
      <IBU_MIN>15.00000000</IBU_MIN>
      <CARB_MIN>0.00000000</CARB_MIN>
      <COLOR_MAX>50.00000000</COLOR_MAX>
      <CATEGORY_NUMBER>16</CATEGORY_NUMBER>
    </STYLE>
  </RECIPE>
  <RECIPE>
    <AGE>14</AGE>
    <FERMENTATION_STAGES>1</FERMENTATION_STAGES>
    <BATCH_SIZE>6.245929452067852</BATCH_SIZE>
    <SECONDARY_TEMP>21.0</SECONDARY_TEMP>
    <TYPE>Partial Mash</TYPE>
    <BOIL_SIZE>7.570823578264063</BOIL_SIZE>
    <TERTIARY_TEMP>21.0</TERTIARY_TEMP>
    <DISPLAY_OG>0.0</DISPLAY_OG>
    <NAME>KBS Clone</NAME>
    <FG>1.018</FG>
    <EQUIPMENT/>
    <SECONDARY_AGE>0</SECONDARY_AGE>
    <PRIMARY_AGE>14</PRIMARY_AGE>
    <OG>1.094</OG>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <PRIMARY_TEMP>21.0</PRIMARY_TEMP>
    <NOTES>Sumatran coffee
Kona blend cold brew
Hungarian oaks</NOTES>
    <DISPLAY_FG>0.0</DISPLAY_FG>
    <BREWER/>
    <TERTIARY_AGE>0</TERTIARY_AGE>
    <BOIL_TIME>60</BOIL_TIME>
    <EFFICIENCY>80.0</EFFICIENCY>
    <HOPS>
      <HOP>
        <NAME>Nugget</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <ALPHA>14.1</ALPHA>
        <AMOUNT>0.00922743</AMOUNT>
        <USE>Boil</USE>
        <TIME>60</TIME>
        <NOTES>No description</NOTES>
        <TYPE>Hop</TYPE>
        <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
      </HOP>
      <HOP>
        <NAME>Willamette</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <ALPHA>4.5</ALPHA>
        <AMOUNT>0.01133981</AMOUNT>
        <USE>Boil</USE>
        <TIME>25</TIME>
        <NOTES>No description</NOTES>
        <TYPE>Hop</TYPE>
        <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
      </HOP>
      <HOP>
        <NAME>Willamette</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <ALPHA>4.5</ALPHA>
        <AMOUNT>0.01700971</AMOUNT>
        <USE>Boil</USE>
        <TIME>10</TIME>
        <NOTES>No description</NOTES>
        <TYPE>Hop</TYPE>
        <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
      </HOP>
    </HOPS>
    <FERMENTABLES>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Pilsen Light DME</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Extract</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>1.0886217</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>90.87999999999992</YIELD>
        <COLOR>1.899999976158142</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Flaked Oats</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Adjunct</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.27215542</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>71.40999999999977</YIELD>
        <COLOR>2.200000047683716</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Six-row (US)</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Grain</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.22679619</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>75.72999999999993</YIELD>
        <COLOR>1.7999999523162842</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Chocolate Wheat Malt</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Grain</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.11339809</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>71.40999999999977</YIELD>
        <COLOR>400.0</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Roasted Barley</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Grain</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.11339809</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>60.589999999999975</YIELD>
        <COLOR>375.0</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Carafa Special III</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Grain</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.07484274</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>77.89999999999982</YIELD>
        <COLOR>525.0</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Special "B" (Belgian)</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Grain</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.07484274</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>64.9200000000002</YIELD>
        <COLOR>140.0</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
    </FERMENTABLES>
    <MISCS>
      <MISC>
        <AMOUNT_IS_WEIGHT>false</AMOUNT_IS_WEIGHT>
        <AMOUNT>0.02957350</AMOUNT>
        <USE_FOR>Boil</USE_FOR>
        <TYPE>Misc</TYPE>
        <VERSION>1</VERSION>
        <NOTES>Custom misc</NOTES>
        <NAME>Cacao Nibs</NAME>
        <USE>Boil</USE>
        <DISPLAY_AMOUNT>1.0 oz</DISPLAY_AMOUNT>
        <DISPLAY_TIME>5 mins</DISPLAY_TIME>
      </MISC>
      <MISC>
        <AMOUNT_IS_WEIGHT>false</AMOUNT_IS_WEIGHT>
        <AMOUNT>0.08872050</AMOUNT>
        <USE_FOR>Secondary</USE_FOR>
        <TYPE>Misc</TYPE>
        <VERSION>1</VERSION>
        <NOTES>Custom misc</NOTES>
        <NAME>Bourbon</NAME>
        <USE>Secondary</USE>
        <DISPLAY_AMOUNT>3.0 oz</DISPLAY_AMOUNT>
        <DISPLAY_TIME>75 days</DISPLAY_TIME>
      </MISC>
      <MISC>
        <AMOUNT_IS_WEIGHT>false</AMOUNT_IS_WEIGHT>
        <AMOUNT>0.02957350</AMOUNT>
        <USE_FOR>Boil</USE_FOR>
        <TYPE>Misc</TYPE>
        <VERSION>1</VERSION>
        <NOTES>Custom misc</NOTES>
        <NAME>Chocolate Bittersweet</NAME>
        <USE>Boil</USE>
        <DISPLAY_AMOUNT>1.0 oz</DISPLAY_AMOUNT>
        <DISPLAY_TIME>5 mins</DISPLAY_TIME>
      </MISC>
      <MISC>
        <AMOUNT_IS_WEIGHT>false</AMOUNT_IS_WEIGHT>
        <AMOUNT>0.01922278</AMOUNT>
        <USE_FOR>Boil</USE_FOR>
        <TYPE>Misc</TYPE>
        <VERSION>1</VERSION>
        <NOTES>Custom misc</NOTES>
        <NAME>Coffee</NAME>
        <USE>Boil</USE>
        <DISPLAY_AMOUNT>0.65 oz</DISPLAY_AMOUNT>
        <DISPLAY_TIME>5 mins</DISPLAY_TIME>
      </MISC>
      <MISC>
        <AMOUNT_IS_WEIGHT>false</AMOUNT_IS_WEIGHT>
        <AMOUNT>0.01922278</AMOUNT>
        <USE_FOR>Secondary</USE_FOR>
        <TYPE>Misc</TYPE>
        <VERSION>1</VERSION>
        <NOTES>Custom misc</NOTES>
        <NAME>Coffee Cold Brew</NAME>
        <USE>Secondary</USE>
        <DISPLAY_AMOUNT>0.65 oz</DISPLAY_AMOUNT>
        <DISPLAY_TIME>75 days</DISPLAY_TIME>
      </MISC>
      <MISC>
        <AMOUNT_IS_WEIGHT>false</AMOUNT_IS_WEIGHT>
        <AMOUNT>0.02957350</AMOUNT>
        <USE_FOR>Secondary</USE_FOR>
        <TYPE>Misc</TYPE>
        <VERSION>1</VERSION>
        <NOTES>Custom misc</NOTES>
        <NAME>Oak Cubes</NAME>
        <USE>Secondary</USE>
        <DISPLAY_AMOUNT>1.0 oz</DISPLAY_AMOUNT>
        <DISPLAY_TIME>75 days</DISPLAY_TIME>
      </MISC>
    </MISCS>
    <YEASTS>
      <YEAST>
        <NAME>Safale US-05</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Yeast</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.05</AMOUNT>
        <LABORATORY>Fermentis</LABORATORY>
        <PRODUCT_ID>US-05</PRODUCT_ID>
        <MIN_TEMPERATURE>18</MIN_TEMPERATURE>
        <MAX_TEMPERATURE>18</MAX_TEMPERATURE>
        <ATTENUATION>80.0</ATTENUATION>
      </YEAST>
    </YEASTS>
    <WATERS/>
    <MASH>
      <TUN_WEIGHT>160.00000000</TUN_WEIGHT>
      <GRAIN_TEMP>22.22222220</GRAIN_TEMP>
      <VERSION>1</VERSION>
      <NAME>BIAB, Medium Body</NAME>
      <NOTES>Brew in a bag method where the full boil volume is mashed within the boil vessel and then the grains are withdrawn at the end of the mash.  No active sparging is required.  This is a medium body beer profile.</NOTES>
      <TUN_SPECIFIC_HEAT>0.30000000</TUN_SPECIFIC_HEAT>
      <EQUIP_ADJUST>FALSE</EQUIP_ADJUST>
      <TUN_TEMP>22.22222220</TUN_TEMP>
      <SPARGE_TEMP>75.60000000</SPARGE_TEMP>
      <PH>5.20000000</PH>
      <MASH_STEPS>
        <MASH_STEP>
          <RAMP_TIME>10.00000000</RAMP_TIME>
          <STEP_TEMP>66.70000000</STEP_TEMP>
          <INFUSE_AMOUNT>8.44625685</INFUSE_AMOUNT>
          <END_TIME>66.70000000</END_TIME>
          <STEP_TIME>75.00000000</STEP_TIME>
          <TYPE>Infusion</TYPE>
          <VERSION>1</VERSION>
          <NAME>Saccharification</NAME>
        </MASH_STEP>
        <MASH_STEP>
          <RAMP_TIME>7.00000000</RAMP_TIME>
          <STEP_TEMP>75.55555560</STEP_TEMP>
          <INFUSE_AMOUNT>0.00000000</INFUSE_AMOUNT>
          <END_TIME>75.55555560</END_TIME>
          <STEP_TIME>10.00000000</STEP_TIME>
          <TYPE>Temperature</TYPE>
          <VERSION>1</VERSION>
          <NAME>Mash Out</NAME>
        </MASH_STEP>
      </MASH_STEPS>
    </MASH>
    <STYLE>
      <PROFILE>Aroma: Rich and complex, with variable amounts of roasted grains, maltiness, fruity esters, hops, and alcohol. The roasted malt character can take on coffee, dark chocolate, or slightly burnt tones and can be light to moderately strong. The malt aroma can be subtle to rich and barleywine-like, depending on the gravity and grain bill. May optionally show a slight specialty malt character (e.g., caramel), but this should only add complexity and not dominate. Fruity esters may be low to moderately strong, and may take on a complex, dark fruit (e.g., plums, prunes, raisins) character. Hop aroma can be very low to quite aggressive, and may contain any hop variety. An alcohol character may be present, but shouldn’t be sharp, hot or solventy. Aged versions may have a slight vinous or portlike quality, but shouldn’t be sour. No diacetyl. The balance can vary with any of the aroma elements taking center stage. Not all possible aromas described need be present; many interpretations are possible. Aging affects the intensity, balance and smoothness of aromatics. Appearance: Color may range from very dark reddish-brown to jet black. Opaque. Deep tan to dark brown head. Generally has a well-formed head, although head retention may be low to moderate. High alcohol and viscosity may be visible in “legs” when beer is swirled in a glass. Flavor: Rich, deep, complex and frequently quite intense, with variable amounts of roasted malt/grains, maltiness, fruity esters, hop bitterness and flavor, and alcohol. Medium to aggressively high bitterness. Medium-low to high hop flavor (any variety). Moderate to aggressively high roasted malt/grain flavors can suggest bittersweet or unsweetened chocolate, cocoa, and/or strong coffee. A slightly burnt grain, burnt currant or tarry character may be evident. Fruity esters may be low to intense, and can take on a dark fruit character (raisins, plums, or prunes). Malt backbone can be balanced and supportive to rich and barleywine-like, and may optionally show some supporting caramel, bready or toasty flavors. Alcohol strength should be evident, but not hot, sharp, or solventy. No diacetyl. The palate and finish can vary from relatively dry to moderately sweet, usually with some lingering roastiness, hop bitterness and warming character. The balance and intensity of flavors can be affected by aging, with some flavors becoming more subdued over time and some aged, vinous or port-like qualities developing. Mouthfeel: Full to very full-bodied and chewy, with a velvety, luscious texture (although the body may decline with long conditioning). Gentle smooth warmth from alcohol should be present and noticeable. Should not be syrupy and underattenuated. Carbonation may be low to moderate, depending on age and conditioning.</PROFILE>
      <ABV_MIN>8.00000000</ABV_MIN>
      <CARB_MAX>0.00000000</CARB_MAX>
      <FG_MAX>1.03000000</FG_MAX>
      <IBU_MAX>90.00000000</IBU_MAX>
      <TYPE>Ale</TYPE>
      <NAME>Imperial Stout</NAME>
      <STYLE_GUIDE>BJCP 2008</STYLE_GUIDE>
      <OG_MIN>1.07500000</OG_MIN>
      <CATEGORY>Stout</CATEGORY>
      <OG_MAX>1.11500000</OG_MAX>
      <COLOR_MIN>30.00000000</COLOR_MIN>
      <ABV_MAX>12.00000000</ABV_MAX>
      <EXAMPLES>Three Floyd’s Dark Lord, Bell’s Expedition Stout, North Coast Old Rasputin Imperial Stout, Stone Imperial Stout, Samuel Smith Imperial Stout, Scotch Irish Tsarina Katarina Imperial Stout, Thirsty Dog Siberian Night, Deschutes The Abyss, Great Divide Yeti, Southampton Russian Imperial Stout, Rogue Imperial Stout, Bear Republic Big Bear Black Stout, Great Lakes Blackout Stout, Avery The Czar, Founders Imperial Stout, Victory Storm King, Brooklyn Black Chocolate Stout</EXAMPLES>
      <INGREDIENTS>Well-modified pale malt, with generous quantities of roasted malts and/or grain. May have a complex grain bill using virtually any variety of malt. Any type of hops may be used. Alkaline water balances the abundance of acidic roasted grain in the grist. American or English ale yeast.</INGREDIENTS>
      <FG_MIN>1.01800000</FG_MIN>
      <STYLE_LETTER>F</STYLE_LETTER>
      <VERSION>1</VERSION>
      <NOTES>An intensely flavored, big, dark ale. Roasty, fruity, and bittersweet, with a noticeable alcohol presence. Dark fruit flavors meld with roasty, burnt, or almost tarlike sensations. Like a black barleywine with every dimension of flavor coming into play. Brewed to high gravity and hopping level in England for export to the Baltic States and Russia. Said to be popular with the Russian Imperial Court. Today is even more popular with American craft brewers, who have extended the style with unique American characteristics. Variations exist, with English and American interpretations (predictably, the American versions have more bitterness, roasted character, and finishing hops, while the English varieties reflect a more complex specialty malt character and a more forward ester profile). The wide range of allowable characteristics allow for maximum brewer creativity.</NOTES>
      <IBU_MIN>50.00000000</IBU_MIN>
      <CARB_MIN>0.00000000</CARB_MIN>
      <COLOR_MAX>40.00000000</COLOR_MAX>
      <CATEGORY_NUMBER>13</CATEGORY_NUMBER>
    </STYLE>
  </RECIPE>
  <RECIPE>
    <AGE>14</AGE>
    <FERMENTATION_STAGES>1</FERMENTATION_STAGES>
    <BATCH_SIZE>4.731764793395996</BATCH_SIZE>
    <SECONDARY_TEMP>21.0</SECONDARY_TEMP>
    <TYPE>Partial Mash</TYPE>
    <BOIL_SIZE>9.463529472830079</BOIL_SIZE>
    <TERTIARY_TEMP>21.0</TERTIARY_TEMP>
    <DISPLAY_OG>0.0</DISPLAY_OG>
    <NAME>Kitchen Sink Amber</NAME>
    <FG>1.043</FG>
    <EQUIPMENT/>
    <SECONDARY_AGE>0</SECONDARY_AGE>
    <PRIMARY_AGE>14</PRIMARY_AGE>
    <OG>1.043</OG>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <PRIMARY_TEMP>21.0</PRIMARY_TEMP>
    <NOTES/>
    <DISPLAY_FG>0.0</DISPLAY_FG>
    <BREWER/>
    <TERTIARY_AGE>0</TERTIARY_AGE>
    <BOIL_TIME>60</BOIL_TIME>
    <EFFICIENCY>75.0</EFFICIENCY>
    <HOPS/>
    <FERMENTABLES>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Wheat DME</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Extract</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.45359237</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>80.06000000000016</YIELD>
        <COLOR>3.0</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Honey Malt (Canadian)</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Grain</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.11339809</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>64.9200000000002</YIELD>
        <COLOR>18.0</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Biscuit (Belgian)</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Grain</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.09071847</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>75.72999999999993</YIELD>
        <COLOR>24.0</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Crystal 40L</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Grain</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.11343012704174228</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>73.91304347826093</YIELD>
        <COLOR>40.0</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
    </FERMENTABLES>
    <MISCS/>
    <YEASTS/>
    <WATERS/>
    <MASH>
      <TUN_WEIGHT>0.00000000</TUN_WEIGHT>
      <GRAIN_TEMP>20.00000000</GRAIN_TEMP>
      <VERSION>1</VERSION>
      <NAME>New Mash Profile</NAME>
      <NOTES/>
      <TUN_SPECIFIC_HEAT>0.00000000</TUN_SPECIFIC_HEAT>
      <EQUIP_ADJUST>FALSE</EQUIP_ADJUST>
      <TUN_TEMP>20.00000000</TUN_TEMP>
      <SPARGE_TEMP>75.55550000</SPARGE_TEMP>
      <PH>7.00000000</PH>
      <MASH_STEPS/>
    </MASH>
    <STYLE>
      <PROFILE/>
      <ABV_MIN>0.00000000</ABV_MIN>
      <CARB_MAX>0.00000000</CARB_MAX>
      <FG_MAX>1.01500000</FG_MAX>
      <IBU_MAX>40.00000000</IBU_MAX>
      <TYPE/>
      <NAME>American Amber Ale</NAME>
      <STYLE_GUIDE/>
      <OG_MIN>1.04500000</OG_MIN>
      <CATEGORY/>
      <OG_MAX>1.06000000</OG_MAX>
      <COLOR_MIN>10.00000000</COLOR_MIN>
      <ABV_MAX>100.00000000</ABV_MAX>
      <EXAMPLES/>
      <INGREDIENTS/>
      <FG_MIN>1.01000000</FG_MIN>
      <STYLE_LETTER/>
      <VERSION>1</VERSION>
      <NOTES/>
      <IBU_MIN>25.00000000</IBU_MIN>
      <CARB_MIN>0.00000000</CARB_MIN>
      <COLOR_MAX>17.00000000</COLOR_MAX>
      <CATEGORY_NUMBER/>
    </STYLE>
  </RECIPE>
  <RECIPE>
    <AGE>14</AGE>
    <FERMENTATION_STAGES>1</FERMENTATION_STAGES>
    <BATCH_SIZE>4.731764736415039</BATCH_SIZE>
    <SECONDARY_TEMP>21.0</SECONDARY_TEMP>
    <TYPE>Partial Mash</TYPE>
    <BOIL_SIZE>6.624470630981055</BOIL_SIZE>
    <TERTIARY_TEMP>21.0</TERTIARY_TEMP>
    <DISPLAY_OG>0.0</DISPLAY_OG>
    <NAME>Nutty Brown Ale</NAME>
    <FG>1.012</FG>
    <EQUIPMENT/>
    <SECONDARY_AGE>0</SECONDARY_AGE>
    <PRIMARY_AGE>14</PRIMARY_AGE>
    <OG>1.053</OG>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <PRIMARY_TEMP>21.0</PRIMARY_TEMP>
    <NOTES>Efficiency was too low, added .25lb more DME to compensate for it.</NOTES>
    <DISPLAY_FG>0.0</DISPLAY_FG>
    <BREWER/>
    <TERTIARY_AGE>0</TERTIARY_AGE>
    <BOIL_TIME>60</BOIL_TIME>
    <EFFICIENCY>50.0</EFFICIENCY>
    <HOPS>
      <HOP>
        <NAME>Nugget</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <ALPHA>14.6</ALPHA>
        <AMOUNT>8.5049E-4</AMOUNT>
        <USE>Boil</USE>
        <TIME>60</TIME>
        <NOTES>No description</NOTES>
        <TYPE>Hop</TYPE>
        <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
      </HOP>
      <HOP>
        <NAME>Kent Golding</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <ALPHA>5.6</ALPHA>
        <AMOUNT>0.00425243</AMOUNT>
        <USE>Boil</USE>
        <TIME>30</TIME>
        <NOTES>No description</NOTES>
        <TYPE>Hop</TYPE>
        <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
      </HOP>
      <HOP>
        <NAME>Kent Golding</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <ALPHA>5.6</ALPHA>
        <AMOUNT>0.0056699</AMOUNT>
        <USE>Boil</USE>
        <TIME>15</TIME>
        <NOTES>No description</NOTES>
        <TYPE>Hop</TYPE>
        <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
      </HOP>
    </HOPS>
    <FERMENTABLES>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Golden Light DME</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Extract</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.45359237</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>93.04999999999984</YIELD>
        <COLOR>11.0</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Two-row (US)</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Grain</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.15592238</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>80.06000000000016</YIELD>
        <COLOR>1.7999999523162842</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Munich (US)</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Grain</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.14174762</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>71.40999999999977</YIELD>
        <COLOR>20.0</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Biscuit (Belgian)</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Grain</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.09922333</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>75.72999999999993</YIELD>
        <COLOR>24.0</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Chocolate Wheat Malt</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Grain</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.059534</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>71.40999999999977</YIELD>
        <COLOR>400.0</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Crystal 40L</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Grain</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.05102914</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>73.5700000000001</YIELD>
        <COLOR>40.0</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Flaked Oats</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Adjunct</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.05102914</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>71.40999999999977</YIELD>
        <COLOR>2.200000047683716</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
    </FERMENTABLES>
    <MISCS>
      <MISC>
        <AMOUNT_IS_WEIGHT>false</AMOUNT_IS_WEIGHT>
        <AMOUNT>0.02957350</AMOUNT>
        <USE_FOR>Boil</USE_FOR>
        <TYPE>Misc</TYPE>
        <VERSION>1</VERSION>
        <NOTES>Custom misc</NOTES>
        <NAME>Chocolate Bittersweet</NAME>
        <USE>Boil</USE>
        <DISPLAY_AMOUNT>1.0 oz</DISPLAY_AMOUNT>
        <DISPLAY_TIME>5 mins</DISPLAY_TIME>
      </MISC>
    </MISCS>
    <YEASTS>
      <YEAST>
        <NAME>Safale S-04</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Yeast</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.05</AMOUNT>
        <LABORATORY>Fermentis</LABORATORY>
        <PRODUCT_ID>S-04</PRODUCT_ID>
        <MIN_TEMPERATURE>17</MIN_TEMPERATURE>
        <MAX_TEMPERATURE>17</MAX_TEMPERATURE>
        <ATTENUATION>75.0</ATTENUATION>
      </YEAST>
    </YEASTS>
    <WATERS/>
    <MASH>
      <TUN_WEIGHT>160.00000000</TUN_WEIGHT>
      <GRAIN_TEMP>22.22222220</GRAIN_TEMP>
      <VERSION>1</VERSION>
      <NAME>BIAB, Medium Body</NAME>
      <NOTES>Brew in a bag method where the full boil volume is mashed within the boil vessel and then the grains are withdrawn at the end of the mash.  No active sparging is required.  This is a medium body beer profile.</NOTES>
      <TUN_SPECIFIC_HEAT>0.30000000</TUN_SPECIFIC_HEAT>
      <EQUIP_ADJUST>FALSE</EQUIP_ADJUST>
      <TUN_TEMP>22.22222220</TUN_TEMP>
      <SPARGE_TEMP>75.60000000</SPARGE_TEMP>
      <PH>5.20000000</PH>
      <MASH_STEPS>
        <MASH_STEP>
          <RAMP_TIME>10.00000000</RAMP_TIME>
          <STEP_TEMP>66.70000000</STEP_TEMP>
          <INFUSE_AMOUNT>7.18295624</INFUSE_AMOUNT>
          <END_TIME>66.70000000</END_TIME>
          <STEP_TIME>75.00000000</STEP_TIME>
          <TYPE>Infusion</TYPE>
          <VERSION>1</VERSION>
          <NAME>Saccharification</NAME>
        </MASH_STEP>
        <MASH_STEP>
          <RAMP_TIME>7.00000000</RAMP_TIME>
          <STEP_TEMP>75.55555560</STEP_TEMP>
          <INFUSE_AMOUNT>0.00000000</INFUSE_AMOUNT>
          <END_TIME>75.55555560</END_TIME>
          <STEP_TIME>10.00000000</STEP_TIME>
          <TYPE>Temperature</TYPE>
          <VERSION>1</VERSION>
          <NAME>Mash Out</NAME>
        </MASH_STEP>
      </MASH_STEPS>
    </MASH>
    <STYLE>
      <PROFILE>Aroma: Malt aroma with mild roastiness should be evident, and may have a chocolaty quality. May also show some nonroasted malt character in support (caramelly, grainy, bready, nutty, toffee-like and/or sweet). English hop aroma moderate to none. Fruity esters moderate to none. Diacetyl low to none. Appearance: Light brown to dark brown in color, often with ruby highlights when held up to light. Good clarity, although may approach being opaque. Moderate off-white to light tan head with good to fair retention. Flavor: Malt flavor includes a mild to moderate roastiness (frequently with a chocolate character) and often a significant caramel, nutty, and/or toffee character. May have other secondary flavors such as coffee, licorice, biscuits or toast in support. Should not have a significant black malt character (acrid, burnt, or harsh roasted flavors), although small amounts may contribute a bitter chocolate complexity. English hop flavor moderate to none. Medium-low to medium hop bitterness will vary the balance from slightly malty to slightly bitter. Usually fairly well attenuated, although somewhat sweet versions exist. Diacetyl should be moderately low to none. Moderate to low fruity esters. Mouthfeel: Medium-light to medium body. Moderately low to moderately high carbonation.</PROFILE>
      <ABV_MIN>4.00000000</ABV_MIN>
      <CARB_MAX>0.00000000</CARB_MAX>
      <FG_MAX>1.01400000</FG_MAX>
      <IBU_MAX>35.00000000</IBU_MAX>
      <TYPE>Ale</TYPE>
      <NAME>Brown Porter</NAME>
      <STYLE_GUIDE>BJCP 2008</STYLE_GUIDE>
      <OG_MIN>1.04000000</OG_MIN>
      <CATEGORY>Porter</CATEGORY>
      <OG_MAX>1.05200000</OG_MAX>
      <COLOR_MIN>20.00000000</COLOR_MIN>
      <ABV_MAX>5.40000000</ABV_MAX>
      <EXAMPLES>Fuller's London Porter, Samuel Smith Taddy Porter, Burton Bridge Burton Porter, RCH Old Slug Porter, Nethergate Old Growler Porter, Hambleton Nightmare Porter, Harvey’s Tom Paine Original Old Porter, Salopian Entire Butt English Porter, St. Peters Old-Style Porter, Shepherd Neame Original Porter, Flag Porter, Wasatch Polygamy Porter</EXAMPLES>
      <INGREDIENTS>English ingredients are most common. May contain several malts, including chocolate and/or other dark roasted malts and caramel-type malts. Historical versions would use a significant amount of brown malt. Usually does not contain large amounts of black patent malt or roasted barley. English hops are most common, but are usually subdued. London or Dublin-type water (moderate carbonate hardness) is traditional. English or Irish ale yeast, or occasionally lager yeast, is used. May contain a moderate amount of adjuncts (sugars, maize, molasses, treacle, etc.).</INGREDIENTS>
      <FG_MIN>1.00800000</FG_MIN>
      <STYLE_LETTER>A</STYLE_LETTER>
      <VERSION>1</VERSION>
      <NOTES>A fairly substantial English dark ale with restrained roasty characteristics. Originating in England, porter evolved from a blend of beers or gyles known as “Entire.” A precursor to stout. Said to have been favored by porters and other physical laborers. Differs from a robust porter in that it usually has softer, sweeter and more caramelly flavors, lower gravities, and usually less alcohol. More substance and roast than a brown ale. Higher in gravity than a dark mild. Some versions are fermented with lager yeast. Balance tends toward malt more than hops. Usually has an “English” character. Historical versions with Brettanomyces, sourness, or smokiness should be entered in the Specialty Beer category (23).</NOTES>
      <IBU_MIN>18.00000000</IBU_MIN>
      <CARB_MIN>0.00000000</CARB_MIN>
      <COLOR_MAX>30.00000000</COLOR_MAX>
      <CATEGORY_NUMBER>12</CATEGORY_NUMBER>
    </STYLE>
  </RECIPE>
  <RECIPE>
    <AGE>14</AGE>
    <FERMENTATION_STAGES>1</FERMENTATION_STAGES>
    <BATCH_SIZE>4.731764736415039</BATCH_SIZE>
    <SECONDARY_TEMP>21.0</SECONDARY_TEMP>
    <TYPE>Partial Mash</TYPE>
    <BOIL_SIZE>6.624470630981055</BOIL_SIZE>
    <TERTIARY_TEMP>21.0</TERTIARY_TEMP>
    <DISPLAY_OG>0.0</DISPLAY_OG>
    <NAME>Spiced Saison</NAME>
    <FG>1.003</FG>
    <EQUIPMENT/>
    <SECONDARY_AGE>0</SECONDARY_AGE>
    <PRIMARY_AGE>14</PRIMARY_AGE>
    <OG>1.048</OG>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <PRIMARY_TEMP>21.0</PRIMARY_TEMP>
    <NOTES/>
    <DISPLAY_FG>0.0</DISPLAY_FG>
    <BREWER/>
    <TERTIARY_AGE>0</TERTIARY_AGE>
    <BOIL_TIME>60</BOIL_TIME>
    <EFFICIENCY>75.0</EFFICIENCY>
    <HOPS>
      <HOP>
        <NAME>Saaz</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <ALPHA>2.2</ALPHA>
        <AMOUNT>0.00566990463296951</AMOUNT>
        <USE>First Wort</USE>
        <TIME>60</TIME>
        <NOTES>No description</NOTES>
        <TYPE>Hop</TYPE>
        <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
      </HOP>
      <HOP>
        <NAME>Hersbrucker</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <ALPHA>2.0</ALPHA>
        <AMOUNT>0.01133980926593902</AMOUNT>
        <USE>Boil</USE>
        <TIME>25</TIME>
        <NOTES>No description</NOTES>
        <TYPE>Hop</TYPE>
        <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
      </HOP>
      <HOP>
        <NAME>Saaz</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <ALPHA>2.2</ALPHA>
        <AMOUNT>0.00566990463296951</AMOUNT>
        <USE>Boil</USE>
        <TIME>5</TIME>
        <NOTES>No description</NOTES>
        <TYPE>Hop</TYPE>
        <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
      </HOP>
      <HOP>
        <NAME>Nugget</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <ALPHA>14.6</ALPHA>
        <AMOUNT>8.504856949454265E-4</AMOUNT>
        <USE>Boil</USE>
        <TIME>60</TIME>
        <NOTES>Primarily for bittering. Herbal and spicy. Used for: Ales.</NOTES>
        <TYPE>Hop</TYPE>
        <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
      </HOP>
    </HOPS>
    <FERMENTABLES>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Pilsen Light DME</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Extract</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.45359237</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>90.87999999999992</YIELD>
        <COLOR>1.899999976158142</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Pale Malt (2 Row) US</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Grain</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.18148820326678766</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>78.26086956521745</YIELD>
        <COLOR>2.0</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Biscuit (Belgian)</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Grain</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.04535924</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>75.72999999999993</YIELD>
        <COLOR>24.0</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Wheat DME</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Extract</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.04535924</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>80.06000000000016</YIELD>
        <COLOR>3.0</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Carafa Special III</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Grain</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.02835753176043557</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>69.5652173913044</YIELD>
        <COLOR>500.0</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
    </FERMENTABLES>
    <MISCS>
      <MISC>
        <AMOUNT_IS_WEIGHT>false</AMOUNT_IS_WEIGHT>
        <AMOUNT>0.00492892</AMOUNT>
        <USE_FOR>Boil</USE_FOR>
        <TYPE>Misc</TYPE>
        <VERSION>1</VERSION>
        <NOTES>Custom misc</NOTES>
        <NAME>Pumpkin Pie Spice</NAME>
        <USE>Boil</USE>
        <DISPLAY_AMOUNT>0.9999999999999999 tsp</DISPLAY_AMOUNT>
        <DISPLAY_TIME>5 mins</DISPLAY_TIME>
      </MISC>
      <MISC>
        <AMOUNT_IS_WEIGHT>false</AMOUNT_IS_WEIGHT>
        <AMOUNT>0.01478675</AMOUNT>
        <USE_FOR>Nutty, citrus flavor</USE_FOR>
        <TYPE>Misc</TYPE>
        <VERSION>1</VERSION>
        <NOTES>Contributes a nutty, citrus flavor.</NOTES>
        <NAME>Coriander Seed</NAME>
        <USE>Boil</USE>
        <DISPLAY_AMOUNT>0.5 oz</DISPLAY_AMOUNT>
        <DISPLAY_TIME>5 mins</DISPLAY_TIME>
      </MISC>
      <MISC>
        <AMOUNT_IS_WEIGHT>false</AMOUNT_IS_WEIGHT>
        <AMOUNT>0.00985785</AMOUNT>
        <USE_FOR>Boil</USE_FOR>
        <TYPE>Misc</TYPE>
        <VERSION>1</VERSION>
        <NOTES>Custom misc</NOTES>
        <NAME>Black pepper</NAME>
        <USE>Boil</USE>
        <DISPLAY_AMOUNT>1.9999999999999998 tsp</DISPLAY_AMOUNT>
        <DISPLAY_TIME>5 mins</DISPLAY_TIME>
      </MISC>
    </MISCS>
    <YEASTS>
      <YEAST>
        <NAME>Belle Saison</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Yeast</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.05</AMOUNT>
        <LABORATORY>Danstar</LABORATORY>
        <PRODUCT_ID>Belle Saison</PRODUCT_ID>
        <MIN_TEMPERATURE>21</MIN_TEMPERATURE>
        <MAX_TEMPERATURE>21</MAX_TEMPERATURE>
        <ATTENUATION>92.0</ATTENUATION>
      </YEAST>
    </YEASTS>
    <WATERS/>
    <MASH>
      <TUN_WEIGHT>160.00000000</TUN_WEIGHT>
      <GRAIN_TEMP>22.22222220</GRAIN_TEMP>
      <VERSION>1</VERSION>
      <NAME>BIAB, Light Body</NAME>
      <NOTES>Brew in a bag method where the full boil volume is mashed within the boil vessel and then the grains are withdrawn at the end of the mash.  No active sparging is required.  This is a light body beer profile.</NOTES>
      <TUN_SPECIFIC_HEAT>0.30000000</TUN_SPECIFIC_HEAT>
      <EQUIP_ADJUST>FALSE</EQUIP_ADJUST>
      <TUN_TEMP>22.22222220</TUN_TEMP>
      <SPARGE_TEMP>75.60000000</SPARGE_TEMP>
      <PH>5.20000000</PH>
      <MASH_STEPS>
        <MASH_STEP>
          <RAMP_TIME>10.00000000</RAMP_TIME>
          <STEP_TEMP>64.40000000</STEP_TEMP>
          <INFUSE_AMOUNT>6.87967561</INFUSE_AMOUNT>
          <END_TIME>64.40000000</END_TIME>
          <STEP_TIME>90.00000000</STEP_TIME>
          <TYPE>Infusion</TYPE>
          <VERSION>1</VERSION>
          <NAME>Saccharification</NAME>
        </MASH_STEP>
        <MASH_STEP>
          <RAMP_TIME>7.00000000</RAMP_TIME>
          <STEP_TEMP>75.55555560</STEP_TEMP>
          <INFUSE_AMOUNT>0.00000000</INFUSE_AMOUNT>
          <END_TIME>75.55555560</END_TIME>
          <STEP_TIME>10.00000000</STEP_TIME>
          <TYPE>Temperature</TYPE>
          <VERSION>1</VERSION>
          <NAME>Mash Out</NAME>
        </MASH_STEP>
      </MASH_STEPS>
    </MASH>
    <STYLE>
      <PROFILE>Aroma: High fruitiness with low to moderate hop aroma and moderate to no herb, spice and alcohol aroma. Fruity esters dominate the aroma and are often reminiscent of citrus fruits such as oranges or lemons. A low to medium-high spicy or floral hop aroma is usually present. A moderate spice aroma (from actual spice additions and/or yeast-derived phenols) complements the other aromatics. When phenolics are present they tend to be peppery rather than clove-like. A low to moderate sourness or acidity may be present, but should not overwhelm other characteristics. Spice, hop and sour aromatics typically increase with the strength of the beer. Alcohols are soft, spicy and low in intensity, and should not be hot or solventy. The malt character is light. No diacetyl. Appearance: Often a distinctive pale orange but may be golden or amber in color. There is no correlation between strength and color. Long-lasting, dense, rocky white to ivory head resulting in characteristic “Belgian lace” on the glass as it fades. Clarity is poor to good though haze is not unexpected in this type of unfiltered farmhouse beer. Effervescent. Flavor: Combination of fruity and spicy flavors supported by a soft malt character, a low to moderate alcohol presence and tart sourness. Extremely high attenuation gives a characteristic dry finish. The fruitiness is frequently citrusy (orange- or lemon-like). The addition of one of more spices serve to add complexity, but shouldn’t dominate in the balance. Low peppery yeast-derived phenols may be present instead of or in addition to spice additions; phenols tend to be lower than in many other Belgian beers, and complement the bitterness. Hop flavor is low to moderate, and is generally spicy or earthy in character. Hop bitterness may be moderate to high, but should not overwhelm fruity esters, spices, and malt. Malt character is light but provides a sufficient background for the other flavors. A low to moderate tart sourness may be present, but should not overwhelm other flavors. Spices, hop bitterness and flavor, and sourness commonly increase with the strength of the beer while sweetness decreases. No hot alcohol or solventy character. High carbonation, moderately sulfate water, and high attenuation give a very dry finish with a long, bitter, sometimes spicy aftertaste. The perceived bitterness is often higher than the IBU level would suggest. No diacetyl. Mouthfeel: Light to medium body. Alcohol level can be medium to medium-high, though the warming character is low to medium. No hot alcohol or solventy character. Very high carbonation with an effervescent quality. There is enough prickly acidity on the tongue to balance the very dry finish. A low to moderate tart character may be present but should be refreshing and not to the point of puckering.</PROFILE>
      <ABV_MIN>5.00000000</ABV_MIN>
      <CARB_MAX>0.00000000</CARB_MAX>
      <FG_MAX>1.01200000</FG_MAX>
      <IBU_MAX>35.00000000</IBU_MAX>
      <TYPE>Ale</TYPE>
      <NAME>Saison</NAME>
      <STYLE_GUIDE>BJCP 2008</STYLE_GUIDE>
      <OG_MIN>1.04800000</OG_MIN>
      <CATEGORY>Belgian and French Ale</CATEGORY>
      <OG_MAX>1.06500000</OG_MAX>
      <COLOR_MIN>5.00000000</COLOR_MIN>
      <ABV_MAX>7.00000000</ABV_MAX>
      <EXAMPLES>Saison Dupont Vieille Provision; Fantome Saison D’Erezee - Printemps; Saison de Pipaix; Saison Regal; Saison Voisin; Lefebvre Saison 1900; Ellezelloise Saison 20; Saison Silly; Southampton Saison; New Belgium Saison; Pizza Port SPF 45; Lost Abbey Red Barn Ale; Ommegang Hennepin</EXAMPLES>
      <INGREDIENTS>Pilsner malt dominates the grist though a portion of Vienna and/or Munich malt contributes color and complexity. Sometimes contains other grains such as wheat and spelt. Adjuncts such as sugar and honey can also serve to add complexity and thin the body. Hop bitterness and flavor may be more noticeable than in many other Belgian styles. A saison is sometimes dry-hopped. Noble hops, Styrian or East Kent Goldings are commonly used. A wide variety of herbs and spices are often used to add complexity and uniqueness in the stronger versions, but should always meld well with the yeast and hop character. Varying degrees of acidity and/or sourness can be created by the use of gypsum, acidulated malt, a sour mash or Lactobacillus. Hard water, common to most of Wallonia, can accentuate the bitterness and dry finish.</INGREDIENTS>
      <FG_MIN>1.00200000</FG_MIN>
      <STYLE_LETTER>C</STYLE_LETTER>
      <VERSION>1</VERSION>
      <NOTES>A refreshing, medium to strong fruity/spicy ale with a distinctive yellow-orange color, highly carbonated, well hopped, and dry with a quenching acidity. A seasonal summer style produced in Wallonia, the French-speaking part of Belgium. Originally brewed at the end of the cool season to last through the warmer months before refrigeration was common. It had to be sturdy enough to last for months but not too strong to be quenching and refreshing in the summer. It is now brewed year-round in tiny, artisanal breweries whose buildings reflect their origins as farmhouses. Varying strength examples exist (table beers of about 5% strength, typical export beers of about 6.5%, and stronger versions of 8%+). Strong versions (6.5%-9.5%) and darker versions (copper to dark brown/black) should be entered as Belgian Specialty Ales (16E). Sweetness decreases and spice, hop and sour character increases with strength. Herb and spice additions often reflect the indigenous varieties available at the brewery. High carbonation and extreme attenuation (85-95%) helps bring out the many flavors and to increase the perception of a dry finish. All of these beers share somewhat higher levels of acidity than other Belgian styles while the optional sour flavor is often a variable house character of a particular brewery.</NOTES>
      <IBU_MIN>20.00000000</IBU_MIN>
      <CARB_MIN>0.00000000</CARB_MIN>
      <COLOR_MAX>14.00000000</COLOR_MAX>
      <CATEGORY_NUMBER>16</CATEGORY_NUMBER>
    </STYLE>
  </RECIPE>
  <RECIPE>
    <AGE>14</AGE>
    <FERMENTATION_STAGES>1</FERMENTATION_STAGES>
    <BATCH_SIZE>5.299576504784843</BATCH_SIZE>
    <SECONDARY_TEMP>21.0</SECONDARY_TEMP>
    <TYPE>Partial Mash</TYPE>
    <BOIL_SIZE>7.570823578264063</BOIL_SIZE>
    <TERTIARY_TEMP>21.0</TERTIARY_TEMP>
    <DISPLAY_OG>0.0</DISPLAY_OG>
    <NAME>Vanilla Latte Stout</NAME>
    <FG>1.007</FG>
    <EQUIPMENT/>
    <SECONDARY_AGE>0</SECONDARY_AGE>
    <PRIMARY_AGE>14</PRIMARY_AGE>
    <OG>1.042</OG>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <PRIMARY_TEMP>21.0</PRIMARY_TEMP>
    <NOTES>Coffee to boil: Decoction made from Indian filter coffee
Cold brew: Eight 'O Clock</NOTES>
    <DISPLAY_FG>0.0</DISPLAY_FG>
    <BREWER/>
    <TERTIARY_AGE>0</TERTIARY_AGE>
    <BOIL_TIME>60</BOIL_TIME>
    <EFFICIENCY>60.0</EFFICIENCY>
    <HOPS>
      <HOP>
        <NAME>Nugget</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <ALPHA>14.1</ALPHA>
        <AMOUNT>0.00283495</AMOUNT>
        <USE>Boil</USE>
        <TIME>60</TIME>
        <NOTES>No description</NOTES>
        <TYPE>Hop</TYPE>
        <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
      </HOP>
    </HOPS>
    <FERMENTABLES>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Pilsen Light DME</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Extract</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.43091276</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>90.87999999999992</YIELD>
        <COLOR>1.899999976158142</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Milk Sugar</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Sugar</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.09071847</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>75.72999999999993</YIELD>
        <COLOR>0.0</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Barley, Flaked</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Grain</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.06803886</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>69.23999999999988</YIELD>
        <COLOR>1.7000000476837158</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Roasted Barley</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Grain</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.06803886</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>60.589999999999975</YIELD>
        <COLOR>300.0</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Two-row (US)</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Grain</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.06803886</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>80.06000000000016</YIELD>
        <COLOR>1.7999999523162842</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Crystal 80L</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Grain</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.04535924</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>73.5700000000001</YIELD>
        <COLOR>80.0</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Chocolate Wheat Malt</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Grain</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.03401943</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>71.40999999999977</YIELD>
        <COLOR>400.0</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
    </FERMENTABLES>
    <MISCS>
      <MISC>
        <AMOUNT_IS_WEIGHT>false</AMOUNT_IS_WEIGHT>
        <AMOUNT>0.01182940</AMOUNT>
        <USE_FOR/>
        <TYPE>Misc</TYPE>
        <VERSION>1</VERSION>
        <NOTES>5oz cold brew made from 0.4 oz of Coffee
Added to secondary</NOTES>
        <NAME>Coffee</NAME>
        <USE>Boil</USE>
        <DISPLAY_AMOUNT>0.4 oz</DISPLAY_AMOUNT>
        <DISPLAY_TIME>2 mins</DISPLAY_TIME>
      </MISC>
      <MISC>
        <AMOUNT_IS_WEIGHT>false</AMOUNT_IS_WEIGHT>
        <AMOUNT>0.01182940</AMOUNT>
        <USE_FOR/>
        <TYPE>Misc</TYPE>
        <VERSION>1</VERSION>
        <NOTES>2 oz espresso shot at flameout, made out of 0.4oz of coffee</NOTES>
        <NAME>Coffee Cold Brew</NAME>
        <USE>Secondary</USE>
        <DISPLAY_AMOUNT>0.4 oz</DISPLAY_AMOUNT>
        <DISPLAY_TIME>7 days</DISPLAY_TIME>
      </MISC>
      <MISC>
        <AMOUNT_IS_WEIGHT>false</AMOUNT_IS_WEIGHT>
        <AMOUNT>0.00887205</AMOUNT>
        <USE_FOR/>
        <TYPE>Misc</TYPE>
        <VERSION>1</VERSION>
        <NOTES>2 tea spoons, added to secondary</NOTES>
        <NAME>Vanilla Extract</NAME>
        <USE>Secondary</USE>
        <DISPLAY_AMOUNT>0.3 oz</DISPLAY_AMOUNT>
        <DISPLAY_TIME>7 days</DISPLAY_TIME>
      </MISC>
    </MISCS>
    <YEASTS>
      <YEAST>
        <NAME>Safale US-05</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Yeast</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.0</AMOUNT>
        <LABORATORY>Fermentis</LABORATORY>
        <PRODUCT_ID>US-05</PRODUCT_ID>
        <MIN_TEMPERATURE>0</MIN_TEMPERATURE>
        <MAX_TEMPERATURE>0</MAX_TEMPERATURE>
        <ATTENUATION>80.0</ATTENUATION>
      </YEAST>
    </YEASTS>
    <WATERS/>
    <MASH>
      <TUN_WEIGHT>160.00000000</TUN_WEIGHT>
      <GRAIN_TEMP>22.22222220</GRAIN_TEMP>
      <VERSION>1</VERSION>
      <NAME>BIAB, Medium Body</NAME>
      <NOTES>Brew in a bag method where the full boil volume is mashed within the boil vessel and then the grains are withdrawn at the end of the mash.  No active sparging is required.  This is a medium body beer profile.</NOTES>
      <TUN_SPECIFIC_HEAT>0.30000000</TUN_SPECIFIC_HEAT>
      <EQUIP_ADJUST>FALSE</EQUIP_ADJUST>
      <TUN_TEMP>22.22222220</TUN_TEMP>
      <SPARGE_TEMP>75.60000000</SPARGE_TEMP>
      <PH>5.20000000</PH>
      <MASH_STEPS>
        <MASH_STEP>
          <RAMP_TIME>10.00000000</RAMP_TIME>
          <STEP_TEMP>66.70000000</STEP_TEMP>
          <INFUSE_AMOUNT>7.85431883</INFUSE_AMOUNT>
          <END_TIME>66.70000000</END_TIME>
          <STEP_TIME>75.00000000</STEP_TIME>
          <TYPE>Infusion</TYPE>
          <VERSION>1</VERSION>
          <NAME>Saccharification</NAME>
        </MASH_STEP>
        <MASH_STEP>
          <RAMP_TIME>7.00000000</RAMP_TIME>
          <STEP_TEMP>75.55555560</STEP_TEMP>
          <INFUSE_AMOUNT>0.00000000</INFUSE_AMOUNT>
          <END_TIME>75.55555560</END_TIME>
          <STEP_TIME>10.00000000</STEP_TIME>
          <TYPE>Temperature</TYPE>
          <VERSION>1</VERSION>
          <NAME>Mash Out</NAME>
        </MASH_STEP>
      </MASH_STEPS>
    </MASH>
    <STYLE>
      <PROFILE/>
      <ABV_MIN>0.00000000</ABV_MIN>
      <CARB_MAX>0.00000000</CARB_MAX>
      <FG_MAX>1.02300000</FG_MAX>
      <IBU_MAX>40.00000000</IBU_MAX>
      <TYPE/>
      <NAME>Milk Stout</NAME>
      <STYLE_GUIDE/>
      <OG_MIN>1.04200000</OG_MIN>
      <CATEGORY/>
      <OG_MAX>1.05600000</OG_MAX>
      <COLOR_MIN>30.00000000</COLOR_MIN>
      <ABV_MAX>100.00000000</ABV_MAX>
      <EXAMPLES/>
      <INGREDIENTS/>
      <FG_MIN>1.01000000</FG_MIN>
      <STYLE_LETTER/>
      <VERSION>1</VERSION>
      <NOTES/>
      <IBU_MIN>25.00000000</IBU_MIN>
      <CARB_MIN>0.00000000</CARB_MIN>
      <COLOR_MAX>40.00000000</COLOR_MAX>
      <CATEGORY_NUMBER/>
    </STYLE>
  </RECIPE>
  <RECIPE>
    <AGE>14</AGE>
    <FERMENTATION_STAGES>1</FERMENTATION_STAGES>
    <BATCH_SIZE>6.245929452067852</BATCH_SIZE>
    <SECONDARY_TEMP>21.0</SECONDARY_TEMP>
    <TYPE>All Grain</TYPE>
    <BOIL_SIZE>7.570823578264063</BOIL_SIZE>
    <TERTIARY_TEMP>21.0</TERTIARY_TEMP>
    <DISPLAY_OG>0.0</DISPLAY_OG>
    <NAME>kitchen sink RIS</NAME>
    <FG>1.017</FG>
    <EQUIPMENT/>
    <SECONDARY_AGE>0</SECONDARY_AGE>
    <PRIMARY_AGE>14</PRIMARY_AGE>
    <OG>1.09</OG>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <PRIMARY_TEMP>21.0</PRIMARY_TEMP>
    <NOTES>Sumatran coffee
Kona blend cold brew
Hungarian oaks</NOTES>
    <DISPLAY_FG>0.0</DISPLAY_FG>
    <BREWER/>
    <TERTIARY_AGE>0</TERTIARY_AGE>
    <BOIL_TIME>60</BOIL_TIME>
    <EFFICIENCY>80.0</EFFICIENCY>
    <HOPS>
      <HOP>
        <NAME>Nugget</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <ALPHA>14.1</ALPHA>
        <AMOUNT>0.00922743</AMOUNT>
        <USE>Boil</USE>
        <TIME>60</TIME>
        <NOTES>No description</NOTES>
        <TYPE>Hop</TYPE>
        <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
      </HOP>
      <HOP>
        <NAME>Willamette</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <ALPHA>4.5</ALPHA>
        <AMOUNT>0.01133981</AMOUNT>
        <USE>Boil</USE>
        <TIME>25</TIME>
        <NOTES>No description</NOTES>
        <TYPE>Hop</TYPE>
        <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
      </HOP>
      <HOP>
        <NAME>Willamette</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <ALPHA>4.5</ALPHA>
        <AMOUNT>0.01700971</AMOUNT>
        <USE>Boil</USE>
        <TIME>10</TIME>
        <NOTES>No description</NOTES>
        <TYPE>Hop</TYPE>
        <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
      </HOP>
    </HOPS>
    <FERMENTABLES>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Barley, Flaked</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Grain</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.18148820326678766</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>69.5652173913044</YIELD>
        <COLOR>1.7000000476837158</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Pale Malt (2 Row) US</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Grain</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>1.3611615245009074</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>78.26086956521745</YIELD>
        <COLOR>2.0</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Chocolate Wheat Malt</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Grain</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.11339809</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>71.40999999999977</YIELD>
        <COLOR>400.0</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Roasted Barley</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Grain</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.13611615245009073</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>60.869565217391354</YIELD>
        <COLOR>375.0</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Carafa Special III</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Grain</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.09074410163339383</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>78.26086956521745</YIELD>
        <COLOR>525.0</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Special "B" (Belgian)</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Grain</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.09074410163339383</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>65.21739130434788</YIELD>
        <COLOR>140.0</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Caramel/Crystal Malt - 40L</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Grain</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.11343012704174228</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>73.91304347826093</YIELD>
        <COLOR>40.0</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Biscuit Malt</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Grain</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.11343012704174228</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>78.26086956521745</YIELD>
        <COLOR>23.0</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Oats, Flaked</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Grain</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.11343012704174228</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>80.43478260869549</YIELD>
        <COLOR>1.0</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Honey Malt</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Grain</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.09074410163339383</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>80.43478260869549</YIELD>
        <COLOR>25.0</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
    </FERMENTABLES>
    <MISCS>
      <MISC>
        <AMOUNT_IS_WEIGHT>false</AMOUNT_IS_WEIGHT>
        <AMOUNT>0.02957350</AMOUNT>
        <USE_FOR>Boil</USE_FOR>
        <TYPE>Misc</TYPE>
        <VERSION>1</VERSION>
        <NOTES>Custom misc</NOTES>
        <NAME>Cacao Nibs</NAME>
        <USE>Boil</USE>
        <DISPLAY_AMOUNT>1.0 oz</DISPLAY_AMOUNT>
        <DISPLAY_TIME>5 mins</DISPLAY_TIME>
      </MISC>
      <MISC>
        <AMOUNT_IS_WEIGHT>false</AMOUNT_IS_WEIGHT>
        <AMOUNT>0.02957350</AMOUNT>
        <USE_FOR>Boil</USE_FOR>
        <TYPE>Misc</TYPE>
        <VERSION>1</VERSION>
        <NOTES>Custom misc</NOTES>
        <NAME>Chocolate Bittersweet</NAME>
        <USE>Boil</USE>
        <DISPLAY_AMOUNT>1.0 oz</DISPLAY_AMOUNT>
        <DISPLAY_TIME>5 mins</DISPLAY_TIME>
      </MISC>
      <MISC>
        <AMOUNT_IS_WEIGHT>false</AMOUNT_IS_WEIGHT>
        <AMOUNT>0.01922278</AMOUNT>
        <USE_FOR>Boil</USE_FOR>
        <TYPE>Misc</TYPE>
        <VERSION>1</VERSION>
        <NOTES>Custom misc</NOTES>
        <NAME>Coffee</NAME>
        <USE>Boil</USE>
        <DISPLAY_AMOUNT>0.65 oz</DISPLAY_AMOUNT>
        <DISPLAY_TIME>5 mins</DISPLAY_TIME>
      </MISC>
      <MISC>
        <AMOUNT_IS_WEIGHT>false</AMOUNT_IS_WEIGHT>
        <AMOUNT>0.08872050</AMOUNT>
        <USE_FOR>Secondary</USE_FOR>
        <TYPE>Misc</TYPE>
        <VERSION>1</VERSION>
        <NOTES>Custom misc</NOTES>
        <NAME>Bourbon</NAME>
        <USE>Secondary</USE>
        <DISPLAY_AMOUNT>3.0 oz</DISPLAY_AMOUNT>
        <DISPLAY_TIME>75 days</DISPLAY_TIME>
      </MISC>
      <MISC>
        <AMOUNT_IS_WEIGHT>false</AMOUNT_IS_WEIGHT>
        <AMOUNT>0.01922278</AMOUNT>
        <USE_FOR>Secondary</USE_FOR>
        <TYPE>Misc</TYPE>
        <VERSION>1</VERSION>
        <NOTES>Custom misc</NOTES>
        <NAME>Coffee Cold Brew</NAME>
        <USE>Secondary</USE>
        <DISPLAY_AMOUNT>0.65 oz</DISPLAY_AMOUNT>
        <DISPLAY_TIME>75 days</DISPLAY_TIME>
      </MISC>
      <MISC>
        <AMOUNT_IS_WEIGHT>false</AMOUNT_IS_WEIGHT>
        <AMOUNT>0.02957350</AMOUNT>
        <USE_FOR>Secondary</USE_FOR>
        <TYPE>Misc</TYPE>
        <VERSION>1</VERSION>
        <NOTES>Custom misc</NOTES>
        <NAME>Oak Cubes</NAME>
        <USE>Secondary</USE>
        <DISPLAY_AMOUNT>1.0 oz</DISPLAY_AMOUNT>
        <DISPLAY_TIME>75 days</DISPLAY_TIME>
      </MISC>
    </MISCS>
    <YEASTS>
      <YEAST>
        <NAME>Safale US-05</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Yeast</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.05</AMOUNT>
        <LABORATORY>Fermentis</LABORATORY>
        <PRODUCT_ID>US-05</PRODUCT_ID>
        <MIN_TEMPERATURE>18</MIN_TEMPERATURE>
        <MAX_TEMPERATURE>18</MAX_TEMPERATURE>
        <ATTENUATION>80.0</ATTENUATION>
      </YEAST>
    </YEASTS>
    <WATERS/>
    <MASH>
      <TUN_WEIGHT>160.00000000</TUN_WEIGHT>
      <GRAIN_TEMP>22.22222220</GRAIN_TEMP>
      <VERSION>1</VERSION>
      <NAME>BIAB, Full Body</NAME>
      <NOTES>Brew in a bag method where the full boil volume is mashed within the boil vessel and then the grains are withdrawn at the end of the mash.  No active sparging is required. This is a full body beer profile.</NOTES>
      <TUN_SPECIFIC_HEAT>0.30000000</TUN_SPECIFIC_HEAT>
      <EQUIP_ADJUST>FALSE</EQUIP_ADJUST>
      <TUN_TEMP>22.22222220</TUN_TEMP>
      <SPARGE_TEMP>75.60000000</SPARGE_TEMP>
      <PH>5.20000000</PH>
      <MASH_STEPS>
        <MASH_STEP>
          <RAMP_TIME>10.00000000</RAMP_TIME>
          <STEP_TEMP>68.90000000</STEP_TEMP>
          <INFUSE_AMOUNT>9.97551023</INFUSE_AMOUNT>
          <END_TIME>68.90000000</END_TIME>
          <STEP_TIME>60.00000000</STEP_TIME>
          <TYPE>Infusion</TYPE>
          <VERSION>1</VERSION>
          <NAME>Saccharification</NAME>
        </MASH_STEP>
        <MASH_STEP>
          <RAMP_TIME>7.00000000</RAMP_TIME>
          <STEP_TEMP>75.55555560</STEP_TEMP>
          <INFUSE_AMOUNT>0.00000000</INFUSE_AMOUNT>
          <END_TIME>75.55555560</END_TIME>
          <STEP_TIME>10.00000000</STEP_TIME>
          <TYPE>Temperature</TYPE>
          <VERSION>1</VERSION>
          <NAME>Mash Out</NAME>
        </MASH_STEP>
      </MASH_STEPS>
    </MASH>
    <STYLE>
      <PROFILE>Aroma: Rich and complex, with variable amounts of roasted grains, maltiness, fruity esters, hops, and alcohol. The roasted malt character can take on coffee, dark chocolate, or slightly burnt tones and can be light to moderately strong. The malt aroma can be subtle to rich and barleywine-like, depending on the gravity and grain bill. May optionally show a slight specialty malt character (e.g., caramel), but this should only add complexity and not dominate. Fruity esters may be low to moderately strong, and may take on a complex, dark fruit (e.g., plums, prunes, raisins) character. Hop aroma can be very low to quite aggressive, and may contain any hop variety. An alcohol character may be present, but shouldn’t be sharp, hot or solventy. Aged versions may have a slight vinous or portlike quality, but shouldn’t be sour. No diacetyl. The balance can vary with any of the aroma elements taking center stage. Not all possible aromas described need be present; many interpretations are possible. Aging affects the intensity, balance and smoothness of aromatics. Appearance: Color may range from very dark reddish-brown to jet black. Opaque. Deep tan to dark brown head. Generally has a well-formed head, although head retention may be low to moderate. High alcohol and viscosity may be visible in “legs” when beer is swirled in a glass. Flavor: Rich, deep, complex and frequently quite intense, with variable amounts of roasted malt/grains, maltiness, fruity esters, hop bitterness and flavor, and alcohol. Medium to aggressively high bitterness. Medium-low to high hop flavor (any variety). Moderate to aggressively high roasted malt/grain flavors can suggest bittersweet or unsweetened chocolate, cocoa, and/or strong coffee. A slightly burnt grain, burnt currant or tarry character may be evident. Fruity esters may be low to intense, and can take on a dark fruit character (raisins, plums, or prunes). Malt backbone can be balanced and supportive to rich and barleywine-like, and may optionally show some supporting caramel, bready or toasty flavors. Alcohol strength should be evident, but not hot, sharp, or solventy. No diacetyl. The palate and finish can vary from relatively dry to moderately sweet, usually with some lingering roastiness, hop bitterness and warming character. The balance and intensity of flavors can be affected by aging, with some flavors becoming more subdued over time and some aged, vinous or port-like qualities developing. Mouthfeel: Full to very full-bodied and chewy, with a velvety, luscious texture (although the body may decline with long conditioning). Gentle smooth warmth from alcohol should be present and noticeable. Should not be syrupy and underattenuated. Carbonation may be low to moderate, depending on age and conditioning.</PROFILE>
      <ABV_MIN>8.00000000</ABV_MIN>
      <CARB_MAX>0.00000000</CARB_MAX>
      <FG_MAX>1.03000000</FG_MAX>
      <IBU_MAX>90.00000000</IBU_MAX>
      <TYPE>Ale</TYPE>
      <NAME>Imperial Stout</NAME>
      <STYLE_GUIDE>BJCP 2008</STYLE_GUIDE>
      <OG_MIN>1.07500000</OG_MIN>
      <CATEGORY>Stout</CATEGORY>
      <OG_MAX>1.11500000</OG_MAX>
      <COLOR_MIN>30.00000000</COLOR_MIN>
      <ABV_MAX>12.00000000</ABV_MAX>
      <EXAMPLES>Three Floyd’s Dark Lord, Bell’s Expedition Stout, North Coast Old Rasputin Imperial Stout, Stone Imperial Stout, Samuel Smith Imperial Stout, Scotch Irish Tsarina Katarina Imperial Stout, Thirsty Dog Siberian Night, Deschutes The Abyss, Great Divide Yeti, Southampton Russian Imperial Stout, Rogue Imperial Stout, Bear Republic Big Bear Black Stout, Great Lakes Blackout Stout, Avery The Czar, Founders Imperial Stout, Victory Storm King, Brooklyn Black Chocolate Stout</EXAMPLES>
      <INGREDIENTS>Well-modified pale malt, with generous quantities of roasted malts and/or grain. May have a complex grain bill using virtually any variety of malt. Any type of hops may be used. Alkaline water balances the abundance of acidic roasted grain in the grist. American or English ale yeast.</INGREDIENTS>
      <FG_MIN>1.01800000</FG_MIN>
      <STYLE_LETTER>F</STYLE_LETTER>
      <VERSION>1</VERSION>
      <NOTES>An intensely flavored, big, dark ale. Roasty, fruity, and bittersweet, with a noticeable alcohol presence. Dark fruit flavors meld with roasty, burnt, or almost tarlike sensations. Like a black barleywine with every dimension of flavor coming into play. Brewed to high gravity and hopping level in England for export to the Baltic States and Russia. Said to be popular with the Russian Imperial Court. Today is even more popular with American craft brewers, who have extended the style with unique American characteristics. Variations exist, with English and American interpretations (predictably, the American versions have more bitterness, roasted character, and finishing hops, while the English varieties reflect a more complex specialty malt character and a more forward ester profile). The wide range of allowable characteristics allow for maximum brewer creativity.</NOTES>
      <IBU_MIN>50.00000000</IBU_MIN>
      <CARB_MIN>0.00000000</CARB_MIN>
      <COLOR_MAX>40.00000000</COLOR_MAX>
      <CATEGORY_NUMBER>13</CATEGORY_NUMBER>
    </STYLE>
  </RECIPE>
  <RECIPE>
    <AGE>14</AGE>
    <FERMENTATION_STAGES>1</FERMENTATION_STAGES>
    <BATCH_SIZE>3.7854117891320316</BATCH_SIZE>
    <SECONDARY_TEMP>21.0</SECONDARY_TEMP>
    <TYPE>Extract</TYPE>
    <BOIL_SIZE>4.731764736415039</BOIL_SIZE>
    <TERTIARY_TEMP>21.0</TERTIARY_TEMP>
    <DISPLAY_OG>0.0</DISPLAY_OG>
    <NAME>Rum Runner Stout</NAME>
    <FG>1.022</FG>
    <EQUIPMENT/>
    <SECONDARY_AGE>0</SECONDARY_AGE>
    <PRIMARY_AGE>14</PRIMARY_AGE>
    <OG>1.091</OG>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <PRIMARY_TEMP>21.0</PRIMARY_TEMP>
    <NOTES/>
    <DISPLAY_FG>0.0</DISPLAY_FG>
    <BREWER/>
    <TERTIARY_AGE>0</TERTIARY_AGE>
    <BOIL_TIME>45</BOIL_TIME>
    <EFFICIENCY>100.0</EFFICIENCY>
    <HOPS>
      <HOP>
        <NAME>Chinook</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <ALPHA>13.0</ALPHA>
        <AMOUNT>0.014174761582423775</AMOUNT>
        <USE>Boil</USE>
        <TIME>45</TIME>
        <NOTES>Strong bittering hop. Heavy and spicy. Used for: Ales, porters, stouts</NOTES>
        <TYPE>Hop</TYPE>
        <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
      </HOP>
    </HOPS>
    <FERMENTABLES>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Special B Malt</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Grain</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.11343012704174228</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>65.21739130434788</YIELD>
        <COLOR>180.0</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Roasted Barley</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Grain</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.05671506352087114</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>54.347826086956324</YIELD>
        <COLOR>300.0</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Dark Dry Extract</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Extract</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.9074410163339383</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>95.65217391304358</YIELD>
        <COLOR>17.5</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
    </FERMENTABLES>
    <MISCS>
      <MISC>
        <AMOUNT_IS_WEIGHT>false</AMOUNT_IS_WEIGHT>
        <AMOUNT>0.04436025</AMOUNT>
        <USE_FOR>Secondary</USE_FOR>
        <TYPE>Misc</TYPE>
        <VERSION>1</VERSION>
        <NOTES>Custom misc</NOTES>
        <NAME>Rum</NAME>
        <USE>Secondary</USE>
        <DISPLAY_AMOUNT>1.5 oz</DISPLAY_AMOUNT>
        <DISPLAY_TIME>15 days</DISPLAY_TIME>
      </MISC>
    </MISCS>
    <YEASTS>
      <YEAST>
        <NAME>Safale S-04</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Yeast</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.05</AMOUNT>
        <LABORATORY>Fermentis</LABORATORY>
        <PRODUCT_ID>S-04</PRODUCT_ID>
        <MIN_TEMPERATURE>17</MIN_TEMPERATURE>
        <MAX_TEMPERATURE>17</MAX_TEMPERATURE>
        <ATTENUATION>75.0</ATTENUATION>
      </YEAST>
    </YEASTS>
    <WATERS/>
    <MASH>
      <TUN_WEIGHT>0.00000000</TUN_WEIGHT>
      <GRAIN_TEMP>20.00000000</GRAIN_TEMP>
      <VERSION>1</VERSION>
      <NAME>New Mash Profile</NAME>
      <NOTES/>
      <TUN_SPECIFIC_HEAT>0.00000000</TUN_SPECIFIC_HEAT>
      <EQUIP_ADJUST>FALSE</EQUIP_ADJUST>
      <TUN_TEMP>20.00000000</TUN_TEMP>
      <SPARGE_TEMP>75.55550000</SPARGE_TEMP>
      <PH>7.00000000</PH>
      <MASH_STEPS/>
    </MASH>
    <STYLE>
      <PROFILE>Aroma: Rich and complex, with variable amounts of roasted grains, maltiness, fruity esters, hops, and alcohol. The roasted malt character can take on coffee, dark chocolate, or slightly burnt tones and can be light to moderately strong. The malt aroma can be subtle to rich and barleywine-like, depending on the gravity and grain bill. May optionally show a slight specialty malt character (e.g., caramel), but this should only add complexity and not dominate. Fruity esters may be low to moderately strong, and may take on a complex, dark fruit (e.g., plums, prunes, raisins) character. Hop aroma can be very low to quite aggressive, and may contain any hop variety. An alcohol character may be present, but shouldn’t be sharp, hot or solventy. Aged versions may have a slight vinous or portlike quality, but shouldn’t be sour. No diacetyl. The balance can vary with any of the aroma elements taking center stage. Not all possible aromas described need be present; many interpretations are possible. Aging affects the intensity, balance and smoothness of aromatics. Appearance: Color may range from very dark reddish-brown to jet black. Opaque. Deep tan to dark brown head. Generally has a well-formed head, although head retention may be low to moderate. High alcohol and viscosity may be visible in “legs” when beer is swirled in a glass. Flavor: Rich, deep, complex and frequently quite intense, with variable amounts of roasted malt/grains, maltiness, fruity esters, hop bitterness and flavor, and alcohol. Medium to aggressively high bitterness. Medium-low to high hop flavor (any variety). Moderate to aggressively high roasted malt/grain flavors can suggest bittersweet or unsweetened chocolate, cocoa, and/or strong coffee. A slightly burnt grain, burnt currant or tarry character may be evident. Fruity esters may be low to intense, and can take on a dark fruit character (raisins, plums, or prunes). Malt backbone can be balanced and supportive to rich and barleywine-like, and may optionally show some supporting caramel, bready or toasty flavors. Alcohol strength should be evident, but not hot, sharp, or solventy. No diacetyl. The palate and finish can vary from relatively dry to moderately sweet, usually with some lingering roastiness, hop bitterness and warming character. The balance and intensity of flavors can be affected by aging, with some flavors becoming more subdued over time and some aged, vinous or port-like qualities developing. Mouthfeel: Full to very full-bodied and chewy, with a velvety, luscious texture (although the body may decline with long conditioning). Gentle smooth warmth from alcohol should be present and noticeable. Should not be syrupy and underattenuated. Carbonation may be low to moderate, depending on age and conditioning.</PROFILE>
      <ABV_MIN>8.00000000</ABV_MIN>
      <CARB_MAX>0.00000000</CARB_MAX>
      <FG_MAX>1.03000000</FG_MAX>
      <IBU_MAX>90.00000000</IBU_MAX>
      <TYPE>Ale</TYPE>
      <NAME>Imperial Stout</NAME>
      <STYLE_GUIDE>BJCP 2008</STYLE_GUIDE>
      <OG_MIN>1.07500000</OG_MIN>
      <CATEGORY>Stout</CATEGORY>
      <OG_MAX>1.11500000</OG_MAX>
      <COLOR_MIN>30.00000000</COLOR_MIN>
      <ABV_MAX>12.00000000</ABV_MAX>
      <EXAMPLES>Three Floyd’s Dark Lord, Bell’s Expedition Stout, North Coast Old Rasputin Imperial Stout, Stone Imperial Stout, Samuel Smith Imperial Stout, Scotch Irish Tsarina Katarina Imperial Stout, Thirsty Dog Siberian Night, Deschutes The Abyss, Great Divide Yeti, Southampton Russian Imperial Stout, Rogue Imperial Stout, Bear Republic Big Bear Black Stout, Great Lakes Blackout Stout, Avery The Czar, Founders Imperial Stout, Victory Storm King, Brooklyn Black Chocolate Stout</EXAMPLES>
      <INGREDIENTS>Well-modified pale malt, with generous quantities of roasted malts and/or grain. May have a complex grain bill using virtually any variety of malt. Any type of hops may be used. Alkaline water balances the abundance of acidic roasted grain in the grist. American or English ale yeast.</INGREDIENTS>
      <FG_MIN>1.01800000</FG_MIN>
      <STYLE_LETTER>F</STYLE_LETTER>
      <VERSION>1</VERSION>
      <NOTES>An intensely flavored, big, dark ale. Roasty, fruity, and bittersweet, with a noticeable alcohol presence. Dark fruit flavors meld with roasty, burnt, or almost tarlike sensations. Like a black barleywine with every dimension of flavor coming into play. Brewed to high gravity and hopping level in England for export to the Baltic States and Russia. Said to be popular with the Russian Imperial Court. Today is even more popular with American craft brewers, who have extended the style with unique American characteristics. Variations exist, with English and American interpretations (predictably, the American versions have more bitterness, roasted character, and finishing hops, while the English varieties reflect a more complex specialty malt character and a more forward ester profile). The wide range of allowable characteristics allow for maximum brewer creativity.</NOTES>
      <IBU_MIN>50.00000000</IBU_MIN>
      <CARB_MIN>0.00000000</CARB_MIN>
      <COLOR_MAX>40.00000000</COLOR_MAX>
      <CATEGORY_NUMBER>13</CATEGORY_NUMBER>
    </STYLE>
  </RECIPE>
  <RECIPE>
    <AGE>14</AGE>
    <FERMENTATION_STAGES>1</FERMENTATION_STAGES>
    <BATCH_SIZE>3.7854117891320316</BATCH_SIZE>
    <SECONDARY_TEMP>21.0</SECONDARY_TEMP>
    <TYPE>Extract</TYPE>
    <BOIL_SIZE>4.731764736415039</BOIL_SIZE>
    <TERTIARY_TEMP>21.0</TERTIARY_TEMP>
    <DISPLAY_OG>0.0</DISPLAY_OG>
    <NAME>Orange Hefweizen</NAME>
    <FG>1.005</FG>
    <EQUIPMENT/>
    <SECONDARY_AGE>0</SECONDARY_AGE>
    <PRIMARY_AGE>14</PRIMARY_AGE>
    <OG>1.044</OG>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <PRIMARY_TEMP>21.0</PRIMARY_TEMP>
    <NOTES/>
    <DISPLAY_FG>0.0</DISPLAY_FG>
    <BREWER/>
    <TERTIARY_AGE>0</TERTIARY_AGE>
    <BOIL_TIME>45</BOIL_TIME>
    <EFFICIENCY>100.0</EFFICIENCY>
    <HOPS>
      <HOP>
        <NAME>Perle</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <ALPHA>8.0</ALPHA>
        <AMOUNT>0.003543690395605944</AMOUNT>
        <USE>Boil</USE>
        <TIME>30</TIME>
        <NOTES>Slightly spicy, minty. Used for: US and German Ales and Lagers.</NOTES>
        <TYPE>Hop</TYPE>
        <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
      </HOP>
    </HOPS>
    <FERMENTABLES>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Wheat Dry Extract</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Extract</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.4537205081669691</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>95.65217391304358</YIELD>
        <COLOR>8.0</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
    </FERMENTABLES>
    <MISCS>
      <MISC>
        <AMOUNT_IS_WEIGHT>false</AMOUNT_IS_WEIGHT>
        <AMOUNT>0.00591470</AMOUNT>
        <USE_FOR>Sweet orange flavor</USE_FOR>
        <TYPE>Misc</TYPE>
        <VERSION>1</VERSION>
        <NOTES>Adds a sweet flavor and aroma, reminiscent of Grand Marnier.</NOTES>
        <NAME>Orange Peel, Sweet</NAME>
        <USE>Boil</USE>
        <DISPLAY_AMOUNT>0.2 oz</DISPLAY_AMOUNT>
        <DISPLAY_TIME>10 mins</DISPLAY_TIME>
      </MISC>
    </MISCS>
    <YEASTS>
      <YEAST>
        <NAME>Safbrew WB-06</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Yeast</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.05</AMOUNT>
        <LABORATORY>Fermentis</LABORATORY>
        <PRODUCT_ID>WB-06</PRODUCT_ID>
        <MIN_TEMPERATURE>21</MIN_TEMPERATURE>
        <MAX_TEMPERATURE>21</MAX_TEMPERATURE>
        <ATTENUATION>86.0</ATTENUATION>
      </YEAST>
    </YEASTS>
    <WATERS/>
    <MASH>
      <TUN_WEIGHT>0.00000000</TUN_WEIGHT>
      <GRAIN_TEMP>20.00000000</GRAIN_TEMP>
      <VERSION>1</VERSION>
      <NAME>New Mash Profile</NAME>
      <NOTES/>
      <TUN_SPECIFIC_HEAT>0.00000000</TUN_SPECIFIC_HEAT>
      <EQUIP_ADJUST>FALSE</EQUIP_ADJUST>
      <TUN_TEMP>20.00000000</TUN_TEMP>
      <SPARGE_TEMP>75.55550000</SPARGE_TEMP>
      <PH>7.00000000</PH>
      <MASH_STEPS/>
    </MASH>
    <STYLE>
      <PROFILE>Aroma: Moderate to strong phenols (usually clove) and fruity esters (usually banana). The balance and intensity of the phenol and ester components can vary but the best examples are reasonably balanced and fairly prominent. Noble hop character ranges from low to none. A light to moderate wheat aroma (which might be perceived as bready or grainy) may be present but other malt characteristics should not. No diacetyl or DMS. Optional, but acceptable, aromatics can include a light, citrusy tartness, a light to moderate vanilla character, and/or a low bubblegum aroma. None of these optional characteristics should be high or dominant, but often can add to the complexity and balance. Appearance: Pale straw to very dark gold in color. A very thick, moussy, long-lasting white head is characteristic. The high protein content of wheat impairs clarity in an unfiltered beer, although the level of haze is somewhat variable. A beer “mit hefe” is also cloudy from suspended yeast sediment (which should be roused before drinking). The filtered Krystal version has no yeast and is brilliantly clear. Flavor: Low to moderately strong banana and clove flavor. The balance and intensity of the phenol and ester components can vary but the best examples are reasonably balanced and fairly prominent. Optionally, a very light to moderate vanilla character and/or low bubblegum notes can accentuate the banana flavor, sweetness and roundness; neither should be dominant if present. The soft, somewhat bready or grainy flavor of wheat is complementary, as is a slightly sweet Pils malt character. Hop flavor is very low to none, and hop bitterness is very low to moderately low. A tart, citrusy character from yeast and high carbonation is often present. Well rounded, flavorful palate with a relatively dry finish. No diacetyl or DMS. Mouthfeel: Medium-light to medium body; never heavy. Suspended yeast may increase the perception of body. The texture of wheat imparts the sensation of a fluffy, creamy fullness that may progress to a light, spritzy finish aided by high carbonation. Always effervescent.</PROFILE>
      <ABV_MIN>4.30000000</ABV_MIN>
      <CARB_MAX>0.00000000</CARB_MAX>
      <FG_MAX>1.01400000</FG_MAX>
      <IBU_MAX>15.00000000</IBU_MAX>
      <TYPE>Ale</TYPE>
      <NAME>Weizen/Weissbier</NAME>
      <STYLE_GUIDE>BJCP 2008</STYLE_GUIDE>
      <OG_MIN>1.04400000</OG_MIN>
      <CATEGORY>German Wheat and Rye Beer</CATEGORY>
      <OG_MAX>1.05200000</OG_MAX>
      <COLOR_MIN>2.00000000</COLOR_MIN>
      <ABV_MAX>5.60000000</ABV_MAX>
      <EXAMPLES>Weihenstephaner Hefeweissbier, Schneider Weisse Weizenhell, Paulaner Hefe-Weizen, Hacker-Pschorr Weisse, Plank Bavarian Hefeweizen, Ayinger Brau Weisse, Ettaler Weissbier Hell, Franziskaner Hefe-Weisse, Andechser Weissbier Hefetrub, Kapuziner Weissbier, Erdinger Weissbier, Penn Weizen, Barrelhouse Hocking Hills Hefe-Weizen, Eisenbahn Weizenbier</EXAMPLES>
      <INGREDIENTS>By German law, at least 50% of the grist must be malted wheat, although some versions use up to 70%; the remainder is Pilsner malt. A traditional decoction mash gives the appropriate body without cloying sweetness. Weizen ale yeasts produce the typical spicy and fruity character, although extreme fermentation temperatures can affect the balance and produce off-flavors. A small amount of noble hops are used only for bitterness.</INGREDIENTS>
      <FG_MIN>1.01000000</FG_MIN>
      <STYLE_LETTER>A</STYLE_LETTER>
      <VERSION>1</VERSION>
      <NOTES>A pale, spicy, fruity, refreshing wheatbased ale. A traditional wheat-based ale originating in Southern Germany that is a specialty for summer consumption, but generally produced year-round. These are refreshing, fast-maturing beers that are lightly hopped and show a unique banana-and-clove yeast character. These beers often don’t age well and are best enjoyed while young and fresh. The version “mit hefe” is served with yeast sediment stirred in; the krystal version is filtered for excellent clarity. Bottles with yeast are traditionally swirled or gently rolled prior to serving. The character of a krystal weizen is generally fruitier and less phenolic than that of the hefe-weizen.</NOTES>
      <IBU_MIN>8.00000000</IBU_MIN>
      <CARB_MIN>0.00000000</CARB_MIN>
      <COLOR_MAX>8.00000000</COLOR_MAX>
      <CATEGORY_NUMBER>15</CATEGORY_NUMBER>
    </STYLE>
  </RECIPE>
  <RECIPE>
    <AGE>14</AGE>
    <FERMENTATION_STAGES>1</FERMENTATION_STAGES>
    <BATCH_SIZE>3.7854117891320316</BATCH_SIZE>
    <SECONDARY_TEMP>21.0</SECONDARY_TEMP>
    <TYPE>Extract</TYPE>
    <BOIL_SIZE>5.678117683698047</BOIL_SIZE>
    <TERTIARY_TEMP>21.0</TERTIARY_TEMP>
    <DISPLAY_OG>0.0</DISPLAY_OG>
    <NAME>Chinook IPA</NAME>
    <FG>1.012</FG>
    <EQUIPMENT/>
    <SECONDARY_AGE>0</SECONDARY_AGE>
    <PRIMARY_AGE>14</PRIMARY_AGE>
    <OG>1.067</OG>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <PRIMARY_TEMP>21.0</PRIMARY_TEMP>
    <NOTES/>
    <DISPLAY_FG>0.0</DISPLAY_FG>
    <BREWER/>
    <TERTIARY_AGE>0</TERTIARY_AGE>
    <BOIL_TIME>45</BOIL_TIME>
    <EFFICIENCY>100.0</EFFICIENCY>
    <HOPS>
      <HOP>
        <NAME>Chinook</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <ALPHA>13.0</ALPHA>
        <AMOUNT>0.003543690395605944</AMOUNT>
        <USE>Boil</USE>
        <TIME>45</TIME>
        <NOTES>Strong bittering hop. Heavy and spicy. Used for: Ales, porters, stouts</NOTES>
        <TYPE>Hop</TYPE>
        <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
      </HOP>
      <HOP>
        <NAME>Chinook</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <ALPHA>13.0</ALPHA>
        <AMOUNT>0.003543690395605944</AMOUNT>
        <USE>Boil</USE>
        <TIME>10</TIME>
        <NOTES>Strong bittering hop. Heavy and spicy. Used for: Ales, porters, stouts</NOTES>
        <TYPE>Hop</TYPE>
        <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
      </HOP>
      <HOP>
        <NAME>Chinook</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <ALPHA>13.0</ALPHA>
        <AMOUNT>0.007087380791211888</AMOUNT>
        <USE>Boil</USE>
        <TIME>1</TIME>
        <NOTES>Strong bittering hop. Heavy and spicy. Used for: Ales, porters, stouts</NOTES>
        <TYPE>Hop</TYPE>
        <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
      </HOP>
    </HOPS>
    <FERMENTABLES>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Caramel/Crystal Malt - 10L</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Grain</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.06805807622504537</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>76.08695652173897</YIELD>
        <COLOR>10.0</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Caramel/Crystal Malt -120L</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Grain</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.022686025408348458</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>71.73913043478242</YIELD>
        <COLOR>120.0</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
      <FERMENTABLE>
        <NAME>Light Dry Extract</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Extract</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.6805807622504537</AMOUNT>
        <YIELD>95.65217391304358</YIELD>
        <COLOR>8.0</COLOR>
        <ADD_AFTER_BOIL>false</ADD_AFTER_BOIL>
      </FERMENTABLE>
    </FERMENTABLES>
    <MISCS/>
    <YEASTS>
      <YEAST>
        <NAME>Safale US-05</NAME>
        <VERSION>0</VERSION>
        <TYPE>Yeast</TYPE>
        <AMOUNT>0.05</AMOUNT>
        <LABORATORY>Fermentis</LABORATORY>
        <PRODUCT_ID>US-05</PRODUCT_ID>
        <MIN_TEMPERATURE>18</MIN_TEMPERATURE>
        <MAX_TEMPERATURE>18</MAX_TEMPERATURE>
        <ATTENUATION>80.0</ATTENUATION>
      </YEAST>
    </YEASTS>
    <WATERS/>
    <MASH>
      <TUN_WEIGHT>0.00000000</TUN_WEIGHT>
      <GRAIN_TEMP>20.00000000</GRAIN_TEMP>
      <VERSION>1</VERSION>
      <NAME>New Mash Profile</NAME>
      <NOTES/>
      <TUN_SPECIFIC_HEAT>0.00000000</TUN_SPECIFIC_HEAT>
      <EQUIP_ADJUST>FALSE</EQUIP_ADJUST>
      <TUN_TEMP>20.00000000</TUN_TEMP>
      <SPARGE_TEMP>75.55550000</SPARGE_TEMP>
      <PH>7.00000000</PH>
      <MASH_STEPS/>
    </MASH>
    <STYLE>
      <PROFILE>Aroma: A prominent to intense hop aroma with a citrusy, floral, perfume-like, resinous, piney, and/or fruity character derived from American hops. Many versions are dry hopped and can have an additional grassy aroma, although this is not required. Some clean malty sweetness may be found in the background, but should be at a lower level than in English examples. Fruitiness, either from esters or hops, may also be detected in some versions, although a neutral fermentation character is also acceptable. Some alcohol may be noted. Appearance: Color ranges from medium gold to medium reddish copper; some versions can have an orange-ish tint. Should be clear, although unfiltered dry-hopped versions may be a bit hazy. Good head stand with white to off-white color should persist. Flavor: Hop flavor is medium to high, and should reflect an American hop character with citrusy, floral, resinous, piney or fruity aspects. Medium-high to very high hop bitterness, although the malt backbone will support the strong hop character and provide the best balance. Malt flavor should be low to medium, and is generally clean and malty sweet although some caramel or toasty flavors are acceptable at low levels. No diacetyl. Low fruitiness is acceptable but not required. The bitterness may linger into the aftertaste but should not be harsh. Medium-dry to dry finish. Some clean alcohol flavor can be noted in stronger versions. Oak is inappropriate in this style. May be slightly sulfury, but most examples do not exhibit this character. Mouthfeel: Smooth, medium-light to medium-bodied mouthfeel without hop-derived astringency, although moderate to medium-high carbonation can combine to render an overall dry sensation in the presence of malt sweetness. Some smooth alcohol warming can and should be sensed in stronger (but not all) versions. Body is generally less than in English counterparts.</PROFILE>
      <ABV_MIN>5.50000000</ABV_MIN>
      <CARB_MAX>0.00000000</CARB_MAX>
      <FG_MAX>1.01800000</FG_MAX>
      <IBU_MAX>70.00000000</IBU_MAX>
      <TYPE>Ale</TYPE>
      <NAME>American IPA</NAME>
      <STYLE_GUIDE>BJCP 2008</STYLE_GUIDE>
      <OG_MIN>1.05600000</OG_MIN>
      <CATEGORY>India Pale Ale (IPA)</CATEGORY>
      <OG_MAX>1.07500000</OG_MAX>
      <COLOR_MIN>6.00000000</COLOR_MIN>
      <ABV_MAX>7.50000000</ABV_MAX>
      <EXAMPLES>Bell’s Two-Hearted Ale, AleSmith IPA, Russian River Blind Pig IPA, Stone IPA, Three Floyds Alpha King, Great Divide Titan IPA, Bear Republic Racer 5 IPA, Victory Hop Devil, Sierra Nevada Celebration Ale, Anderson Valley Hop Ottin’, Dogfish Head 60 Minute IPA, Founder’s Centennial IPA, Anchor Liberty Ale, Harpoon IPA, Avery IPA</EXAMPLES>
      <INGREDIENTS>Pale ale malt (well-modified and suitable for single-temperature infusion mashing); American hops; American yeast that can give a clean or slightly fruity profile. Generally all-malt, but mashed at lower temperatures for high attenuation. Water character varies from soft to moderately sulfate. Versions with a noticeable Rye character (“RyePA”) should be entered in the Specialty category.</INGREDIENTS>
      <FG_MIN>1.01000000</FG_MIN>
      <STYLE_LETTER>B</STYLE_LETTER>
      <VERSION>1</VERSION>
      <NOTES>A decidedly hoppy and bitter, moderately strong American pale ale. An American version of the historical English style, brewed using American ingredients and attitude.</NOTES>
      <IBU_MIN>40.00000000</IBU_MIN>
      <CARB_MIN>0.00000000</CARB_MIN>
      <COLOR_MAX>15.00000000</COLOR_MAX>
      <CATEGORY_NUMBER>14</CATEGORY_NUMBER>
    </STYLE>
  </RECIPE>
</RECIPES>
